Welcome Living Mana Church family. It's
so good to have you here with us to
worship on this Sabbath day. It's a
blessing to have all of you here. It's a
blessing to have us both here in studio
together because if you remember last
week I was here, he was in uh Virginia
and we did it together but he was on the
screen but now he's here. So I'm happy.
>> Yes. But I am happy to be home.
>> Yes, I am happy that you're home and I'm
glad to have all of you here. Please put
in the chat where you are viewing from.
We want to say a special welcome to you.
So, if this is your first time
worshiping with Living Mana Church,
please put a one in the chat and where
you are viewing from, we want to tell
you a little bit more about Living Mana
Online Church. But we are just happy
that you are all here today. So, yes,
please put in the chat where you're
where you're viewing from.
>> Yes. Uh, and I want to say uh we don't
usually do this. We usually do this at
the end of Sabbath school. We talk about
what I'm going to preach.
>> Do it at the beginning. Do it at the
end. It's fine. Um so today you guys um
it is not evangelism Sabbath.
>> Evangelism Sab Sabbath is typically
remember all the people you're seeing
>> is typically at the end of the month but
>> uh in light of recent events uh over the
last week
>> uh which um the last two weeks which
bring up questions about hellfire and
the Sabbath. Uh today's sermon is going
to be on that. So listen, I want to
encourage you. If you are Adventists,
I am going to tell you that what you
will hear today, you haven't heard it
this way before. And I'm talking about
if you've seen the blueprint. I'm
talking about if you've heard my
messages on the Sabbath, on the state of
the dead, on hellfire.
>> Um
um I believe God gave uh God poured
something special out in this particular
message. So please
>> Amen. And then
>> obviously invite people to watch this
message.
>> Please share
>> share this share this link. Share this
link. But we're going to do a little I
don't know if they call it housekeeping,
but a little we're going to ask you to
subscribe uh to the YouTube channel that
you are that you are viewing from and
like subscribe and like and share. So
you have three assignments. Subscribe,
like and share. or if you've already
subscribed, then all you have to do is
two assignments, like and share. So,
definitely share. Um because you know
what? The Sabbath is all over the news.
It's everywhere. Like, you can openly
talk about it because obviously Charlie
Kirk's book just came out on the 9th.
So, everybody is talking about it and so
you can talk about it, too. And then
because of Kirk Cameron, a lot of people
are talking about uh the truth about
Hellfire. So, you can talk about it,
too. And you're definitely going to
learn some new things. Let me not miss
any more of your locations. But we have
John. Hi John Heasley from MacArthur,
Ohio. Always good to see you here. Um
Barbara from Anguela. Always great to
see you as well. We have Simon from
Tanzania. Very good. And Simon's like,
I'm a regular viewer. Yes. And we love
that you are a regular viewer and so
we're happy to see you here. Um, we have
uh Jen from Tennessee. So, welcome. We
have Oh, we have a one from Rwanda. I
think it's probably our first person
from Rwanda. Awesome. All right. So,
>> have you seen the one from Jamaica yet?
>> Oh, I haven't seen the one from Jamaica.
Yay. Definitely. We have We have lots of
uh Jamaican uh viewership, but we're
always happy to get more. Uh, for sure.
>> Amen.
>> You're home. your home. That's right.
Your home of your birth.
>> Um, let's see. And then we have and I
will get for Rwanda. I will tell you a
little bit more about Living Manage
Church. Um, and I don't know your first
name, so that's why I'm just saying
Rwanda. I'm calling you from the country
you're you're viewing from. And then we
have Omen uh Chandler from Rome,
Georgia. That's not too far from where
we are. I've driven through Rome. Okay.
Welcome. Very happy to have you here. We
have uh a viewer from Long Beach,
California. Welcome. Good to see you
here. We have Jason from New York. We um
have St. Louis, Missouri here. Welcome.
Good to see all of you here. All right.
To our first timers, I now see the
first- timer from Jamaica. Welcome. And
then we have Idaho, too. So, welcome,
welcome, welcome. Um you can continue to
put in the chat tell us where you're
viewing from. But I just want to let you
guys know the viewer the um our our
viewer from Rwanda and from Jamaica. Uh
this is a 100% online church. Uh so you
will be able to view uh our our viewing
uh things that we share all throughout
the week. We have mental health um
programs on Mondays. We have health true
health uh programs on it's on health and
it's called true health on Tuesdays. We
have two prayer services on Wednesday
and I'm going to tell you a little bit
more about them at the beginning of the
divine worship service. Um and then we
have Thursday we have young adult um
programming on Thursday with pastor uh
Lwami Richardson. So we are here all
throughout the week. We have many small
groups that you can uh join and again
I'll tell you so much more about that uh
at the beginning of the divine worship
service but we have a community an
international community here on living
mana uh church and I think you will find
what you are looking for just stick
around and continue to check us out.
>> Amen.
>> Yes. But we are thrilled that you that
you are here. All right. Well I think
since you already talked about nope
we're not here for teacher. We have a
second reading.
>> That's right.
>> We have a second reading. We are going
to vote somebody in to be an official
member here at Living Mana Church. So,
okay, this is the second reading for
Cavell
Gratty and Cavell is coming from the
Adventist Fellowship Church in Leburg,
Georgia.
>> All right. So, um, we're going to do as
we typically do. We're going to, uh, ask
for a motion from one of our members.
Um, that will be followed by a second.
And at that time, we will go ahead and
vote Cavil. Uh, is it Grady?
>> Uh, yes. Cavell Grady.
>> Grady. Uh, into into uh
>> into fellowship. I hope I hope we said
the last name right. So,
>> it's probably Gratty. It's okay. So,
we've got a motion and uh we also have
uh a second. All right. Amen. So, let's
go ahead and um
vote uh Cavell into Fellowship of the
Living Man online church. And uh let's
go ahead and put that put a two in the
chat. Put a two in the chat. Um we'll
watch as they come in.
>> Some's already said, "Oh, we're doing a
two instead of one." No, we've already
got the motion. We've got the second.
And now we're voting.
>> Okay. Yep. But with the two. Yeah.
>> Okay. Got it.
>> All right. So, here comes my
>> twos are coming in.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> Yep. They are coming in.
>> All right. So so amazing to be able to
have members um from all around uh the
world and viewing audience from all
around the world as well. So we are
excited every time we get to vote a new
official member into our church.
>> All right. So we want to welcome Cabel.
Uh it is it is official. Um welcome
aboard. Uh we we look forward to um to
fellowship and just seeing how the Lord
is going to use you
>> um in this church to help spread his
mission and his work around the world.
So praise God and Amen. Amen. Amen.
>> So yes, and Caval, I'm not sure if
you're already in a small group and if
you're um have made connections with
other members um on mighty networks, but
I definitely encourage you to do that.
Um, and again, if you don't already
know, you will find out in the divine
worship service, but you've been here,
so I'm sure you already know. But we are
so happy for you to be doing ministry
alongside alongside of us because here
at Living Mana, there are no I got a new
term, screen warmers. Instead of pew
warmers, there's no screen warmers. You
have to be active
>> and doing what God has called you to do.
And we're excited to see uh what God uh
how God is going to use you here at
Living Mana Church.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen. All right.
T-shirt message. An oldie but goody.
>> Faith over fear. Simple.
>> Very simple, but again, not so simple. I
mean,
>> faith over fear. Like this is the one
that spoke to me um this week really. Um
it's like we
it's you know and I was listening to a
sermon this morning where I this pastor
added to what I was thinking but we were
the Bible says we're all given uh a
measure of faith
>> like we have and so and that now he
didn't say this this is what I felt like
the Holy Spirit told me when he said it
but so we all have a measure of faith
that God has given us. So if God has
given it to us, he's given us the right
amount of faith. Just like, you know,
when you're doing a recipe, you got to
put in,
>> you know, a half a cup of this, a cup of
that. So he's given us enough faith for
me, for you.
>> Yeah.
>> For our life to go through what you what
I'm going to personally go through.
>> So we have enough faith. We just have to
accept it. It's already a gift. He's
already given it to us. We just have to
apply it to every situation.
>> Amen. So, um, that is what we, so when
we're feeling fear, we're not applying
the faith that God has already given us.
We just need to like put it on that
situation. And I just had a situation
this week where I found out something
and I was like so discouraged at first
because I was like, God, I've been we
I've been praying about this and, you
know, there's, you know, why isn't this
answered? And then the Holy Spirit, I
say, swooped in pretty quickly.
I say spooked because or I just the Holy
Spirit was already there,
>> but I
heard or focused on what the Holy Spirit
was trying to say at that moment. And it
was like
>> the I've been praying about a lot of
things in this situation and and several
of them have been answered. Yeah.
>> But this one hadn't been answered. So I
was just like, "Yeah, of course you're
going to answer that one because you've
already answered these." And that one
still wasn't answered. But then the Holy
Spirit was like just what I said. He's
like, I've already answered these other
parts of the prayer. Can you trust the
process? And I I'm I'm there's there's a
reason what for whatever reason. I don't
have to understand the reasoning, but
that's coming.
>> So, um, so yeah,
>> and
>> yeah, there's a lot I could say, but
>> this faith over fear, even in that
moment, we have to trust
>> he's given us enough
>> faith, measure of faith, he promised us.
That's a promise.
>> Yeah.
>> It's a fact.
>> Yeah. If he said it, it is. It's
reality.
>> Yeah. It's a choice.
>> It's a choice. We just have to like,
okay, so yeah, I had to choose to
believe what the Holy Spirit was telling
me, of course, like I should be
believing what the Holy Spirit is
saying. God, the Holy Spirit, Jesus,
they can't lie. They're not lying to me.
And so, um, after that happened and
after I accepted that, I really
emotionally felt much better. I even
like because crying over something like
that is what I would normally do. I
really couldn't even cry. Like I said
cry, but the tears didn't come because
God had already kind of given me.
>> Yeah.
>> I was applying the faith even though I
was saying but but what I'm used to like
no cry. You cry over this. No,
>> I can trust God. I don't even have to
cry.
>> So it actually felt odd.
>> Amen.
>> So anyways, that that's where this
t-shirt came from today or this week.
>> Amen.
Well, we're about to
>> start Sabbath school.
>> Start Sabbath school. We're gonna pray.
>> We're gonna pray.
>> And uh we're going to continue for a new
member.
>> Yep. And we're going to continue on in
our reading of the Christian Art of War.
>> Yes, guys. It's been a while.
>> We're still on chapter 4.
>> We've been on chapter four for like
>> chapter four is well there. I love the
book, but chapter 4 is so good. Just,
you know, going through the fruits of
the spirit. Um, but yeah, we're just
taking our and we'll take breaks to do
our question and answers and if we have
to do another Sabbath school topic that
just fits in for the moment, we take
breaks. There's no rush.
>> There's this is we want to really really
get this. We don't want to rush over
anything.
>> But we have our established school panel
just waiting for us to bring them on.
>> So,
>> so we're going to pray
>> uh and uh and then we're going to get
into this this study this morning. So,
let's pray.
>> Amen.
Heavenly Father, we thank you Lord um
for uh first Cavell, Lord um joining our
church. We thank you that um you will
use Cavell in a very powerful and mighty
way, Lord. We trust that. And
>> uh just thank you for adding to to the
body of believers here, Lord. Um Lord,
we pray that as we begin our Sabbath
school, um continuing our study on the
Christian art of the Christian art of
war and specifically the fruit of the
spirit, Lord, we pray that you would
guide our thoughts, be with our guests,
and um Lord, just bless our study. Uh
and we pray this in Jesus name. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen.
All right. Well, we would like to invite
Yes. Michaela. Hi. And Melinda, guys,
welcome back school panel. So good to
see you here. Um I don't think you guys
have been here like on on Sabbath
morning um since you guys did the the
church service a few weeks few weeks
back. So we are just happy to have you
guys here. I know everyone was blessed
by the youth Sabbath, by the sermon, by
the Sabbath school.
>> Yes. Thank you, Michaela, for doing my
announcements and you did such a great
job.
>> Yeah. So, both of Yeah, it was a
blessing. And Kazia,
>> you were awesome, Michaela.
>> So, yes. Great.
>> She's like,
>> yeah. No, it can be like nerve-wracking
to like do all it's it's the whole thing
like you from a communications major to
another great communicator. I You did
great. So, I Yeah.
She's like, "Let's move on."
>> And I think from a from a preacher to
another preacher, we were like, "You're
It was such a blessing. It was such a
blessing, Melinda. It really was."
>> It was truly a blessing. So, we're just
happy to have you guys back.
>> Praise God.
>> Amen.
>> And we can all discuss and talk
together. So, where did we leave off?
>> So, we are uh we're going to be picking
up on the the fruit of gentleness.
And um I will do as I've done
previously. I'm going to go ahead and
read through uh this whole section. And
then what we'll do is uh come back and
begin to comment on it.
>> Okay.
>> So, as you know, as you're following
along um everyone that has requested
this particular chapter in PDF, you
should you should have uh received it or
gained access to it.
>> That's what I should want to talk about
that real quick. Well, just really quick
guys, we're going through the book, The
Christian Art of War, especially to our
first- timers would not know. The
Christian The Christian Art of War is a
book that Pastor Meyers wrote 15 maybe
years ago. Um, and so it is no longer in
print, but you can get it on Mighty
Networks. Uh, we have the first four
chapters that have been released. So
there you can you can get it and be
reading and study with us. And once we
get to the next chapter, of course, it
will be released on Mighty Networks as
well.
>> Yeah. So, uh, we're going to begin with
the gentle way. The word gentleness
describes a disposition rather than an
act. It means mildness, smooth or uh,
smooth or easiness. Christ used this
same word when he said, "Take my yoke
upon you and learn of me, for I am meek
and lowly in heart, and you shall find
rest unto your souls. For my yoke is
easy and my burden is light."
Here the word signifies gracious. The
complete word study dictionary says of
this word, "It is the grace which
pervades the whole nature, mellowing all
which would be harsh and austere." The
spirit of gentleness describes the way
in which the warrior's battle against
the force of darkness should be
executed. While all his energies are to
be engaged in this war against self,
the spirit of gentleness gives it the
appearance of an effortless or smooth
warfare
with graceful flowing movements of the
spirit of God. He is to dominate the
self nature. His battle is to have the
appearance of effortlessness.
This brings us to Ephesians chapter 2.
Ephesians chapter 2 verse uh 8 and N
which says, "For by grace are you saved
through faith and not of yourselves. It
is the gift of God, not of works, lest
any man should boast." This grace or
gentleness of God, however, requires
everything we have, all our energies in
order to truly become effortless.
James 21:17 says, "Even so faith if it
has not works being is dead being
alone."
Effortlessness can be achieved only
through effort. That sounds like
>> oxymora,
>> but effortlessness can be achieved only
through effort. The boxer, the martial
artist, the wrestler reaches a stage of
apparent effortlessness. his movement
full of grace because he has put forth
tireless enduring effort in an art that
brings him joy and art he loves. So it
must be with the warriors for Christ.
Jesus effort effortlessly confounded his
enemies yet it was not without striving
crying and tears. Hebrews 5:7
to achieve the gentle way of Christ.
Effortless uh effortless yet full of
effort, graceful and yet and gentle yet
devastating against self. This must be
our aim.
The there is another aspect of
gentleness which is of great importance
to a warrior of Christ. It is the use of
gentleness or softness as a defense. It
is a known fact that the softer
something is, the better it absorbs a
direct hit. It is pliable, able to adapt
in form, and therefore able to absorb
concentrated attacks. Try breaking a
pillow. It cannot be done.
Make the same attempt with a stick and
see how easily it breaks. The soft the
softest things cannot be snapped. Since
our enemy is often out to break us,
understanding how to be gentle spirited,
soft-spirited means having a spirit not
subject to snapping or breaking.
Mastering the spirit of gentleness makes
us snapresistant in the face of
temptation. The blows of temptation are
absorbed by the gentleness of the spirit
of God.
>> Wow.
So,
I'm going to start off just by actually
talking about the last part of that that
reading first.
>> Um, how many times have we broken,
>> snapped,
>> right?
>> That moment of all right, that's it. I'm
done. We're about I'm about to snap.
>> Yeah.
>> Soft things cannot cannot snap.
>> Cannot snap. Mercy. Um, in order to to
snap, you have to be hard-hearted.
>> Yeah.
>> In order to snap,
>> um, you have to be stubborn. You have to
be resistant, right?
>> Yes.
>> Um,
>> you got to make yourself,
>> right? You're tensed up.
>> Yeah.
>> In this in this uh particular segment
when I'm talking about effortlessness,
right?
uh
you know different different uh
in different sports arenas, right?
>> In basketball,
>> um in football,
uh when someone is really good at
something, what do they say? They make
it look
>> I know what you're thinking right now.
They make effortless by the best shooter
of all time. They make it look
effortless.
>> Effortless,
>> right? Like you're not even trying.
>> They say effortless.
>> And that effortlessness
>> is make it look easy
>> is what we're after,
>> right? How do we how do we gain how do
we do something so much that it becomes
effortless? It becomes
>> like a reflex.
>> Yeah.
>> Kindness. Oh, you cast me out. Gentle.
>> Yeah. You know, you respond, you respond
with gentleness.
>> The Bible says, "A soft answer
>> turns away wrath."
>> So this idea again of um of gentleness
is not should not be considered
weakness,
>> right?
>> It takes strength. It takes practice.
>> Yes.
>> It takes effort.
to absorb blows and not snap
>> and not break
>> and you know when I teaching um
communication
healthy communication to couples and
this is from John Dr. Dr. John Gottman,
but he talks about a soft
startup,
>> a gentle startup. It means like how are
you coming into approaching the
conversation?
You have for you to be able to um the
best way to not cause an argument is to
come with a soft opening
>> comment and statement or whatever. And
soft is gentle. And you know, it's
gentle, it's kind,
>> it's not hard,
>> it's not abrupt,
>> right?
>> It's not mean.
>> And when what happens with the soft
startup, it's like, of course, the
person, your spouse, or whoever has a
choice to respond, um, but when we're
looking at the Bible, we should always,
even if they respond poorly, we should
still be gentle.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Um, okay, we're gonna, um, anyone of you
feel free to jump in.
talk to us about what uh what jumps out
to you in this particular
>> um in this particular fruit uh and and
then we we're going to build on that. So
>> So I don't know Michaela do you have
anything to say because otherwise I
would just start sharing. Um well what I
immediately think of is like the word
grace in comp in relation to this topic
like just
>> something that
is
relating to the situation in this soft
way that just kind of feels effortless
grace. And then that makes me think of
like versus like my grace is sufficient
for you. And like
this this grace from God,
this
this idea of
God's
perfect perfect effortlessness,
but like poured into us and making up
for where we are not gentle, not filled
with grace.
>> So that's what I'm thinking of.
Yeah. It is it is his we don't have it
in us to be gentle.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. It's his spirit that brings
gentleness to us. And and it's funny
because the Bible says that by by nature
we are wrathful. Mhm.
>> So,
if we're wrathful by nature,
>> it's going to take something
supernatural
to to move us from being wrathful by
nature to gentle by nature.
>> Which means which requires a change of
nature.
>> We need the nature of Christ.
>> Yeah. We need the nature of Christ.
And it's kind of, you know, I think
sometimes how there's there's a lot of
times we argue over what nature Christ
had, which
I think the more important
issue is that we have to have the nature
of Christ,
>> right?
>> So,
oh, was he, you know, did he have the
nature of Adam before the fall or the
nature of Adam after the fall? which
where's your position? It really doesn't
I'm not going to say it really doesn't
matter. What I'm going to say is that
the most important thing is that we must
reflect the nature of Christ. I have
seen people I've seen people
arguing over the nature of Christ. And
not there are they're arguing.
>> How dare you? The nature of Christ is
this way and and just losing the nature
of Christ while arguing about which
nature Christ had.
>> I think the average person is not
arguing about the nature of Christ. But
I think
>> there is a there's there's a group
>> there's a group within the church,
right? That the nature of Christ and
where you fall on that question is
absolutely crucial because it's going to
determine A or B. And yet in all that in
all that debate and all that arguing, we
sometimes see you lose the nature of
Christ
>> in trying to defend the nature of
Christ. So I know we're kind of like,
but really really this is exactly what
we're talking about.
>> If we're arguing about the nature of
Christ and yet we don't have that gentle
spirit.
>> Right.
>> Yeah.
>> We don't even say in the chat, we we are
naughty by nature.
Yeah, absolutely. Absolutely. You're
right. We are naughty by nature and we
need to be
>> gentle by nature.
>> That's right.
>> Gentle by nature.
>> Yeah. So, um Okay. I think somebody was
going to say something and I kind of
jumped in real quick.
>> Yeah. Um I was going to actually talk
about something similar. I like
Michaela. Um, I think it's really
interesting how gentleness is like um
how it talked about in the book how we
shouldn't be like snapping and how
gentleness keeps us from snapping. that
really reminds me of how God um you know
in the Bible in Psalms he talks about
how the righteous people are like green
trees and I think it's really
interesting because if you take a twig
and it's like fresh from a tree it's
really really hard to snap it as a when
you take a dried tree
it's not hard to snap it you just go
snap and it's really easy and I think
it's interesting how God calls us to be
green trees
>> I don't
Yeah. Wow. Wow. Yeah.
>> Um that is a very powerful
>> powerful thought, right? Because when
you're dry
>> when you're a dry tree
>> Yeah.
>> you're easy to burn.
>> Easy,
>> right?
>> Dry trees are are easy to
>> to
>> get hot real quick
>> and snap.
Um
and how often that
>> dry trees don't make any fruit,
>> right?
>> And dry trees do not make any fruit.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh that is the truth.
>> Um yeah, that is uh that is actually I
think an excellent excellent point um in
that we're brittle.
>> I like that, Nicole.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. How many of us are walking around
brittle? Right.
>> The smallest thing
and we snap.
>> Yeah.
>> Evidence that the fruit of gentleness
>> is not yet a reality in our lives.
Right.
>> Right.
>> Um
gentleness does not mean as I said um it
doesn't mean just going with whatever,
>> right? Doesn't mean just going with the
flow.
But speaking of going with the flow,
there is a there is a particular
martial arts
that looks like it could defend against
nothing because the entire martial art
is based off of the idea of flow. You
see a lot of old people doing it, right?
Uh, anybody know the martial art I'm
talking about?
>> Yeah, somebody in the chat needs to
because I'm like clueless. I I don't
know anything about martial arts except
what you tell me.
>> Yeah. The the martial art is is very
flowing.
>> Everything you do is flowing and gentle.
>> Yeah.
>> And soft. And the whole idea behind
>> you're actually fighting with I mean
it's actually Yeah. Wow.
>> The whole idea behind this fighting
style called Tai Chi.
>> Okay.
>> Is you're using your enemy's force and
anger and frustration against them.
>> Right. So someone throws a punch, you're
not trying to block the punch. You're
actually just kind of sending them on
their way. Like
>> we talked about, you did talk about
this. We talked about in one of the
earlier chapters,
>> you just go with the you're sending them
with the flow, right?
>> So they're like, "I'm so mad." And they
throw the punch and instead of you
blocking the punch, right? You're just
>> you're just directing the punch. You're
like, "Oh, you're going over there."
Okay.
>> And you send them off over there, right?
>> So, think of think of this as
the
the tai chichi of Christianity, if you
will, right?
>> We're not talking about all the all the
spiritualistic, you know, things that
are invol, but I'm simply saying you're
redirecting. I like that cross
harmonica. You're redirecting their
energy.
>> Redirecting.
>> So, you know, think about how many times
through the day, right? Somebody may
come at you like, you know, and they're
coming in karate style,
>> right? You and it's just like very
out there
and the the Tai Chi person is just like
>> So, you know, I I know it's kind of I'm
using analogies, right?
>> Because Yeah, it makes sense.
>> Yeah. I'm using analogies of of of
worldly systems of fighting,
>> but that's kind of, you know, when Paul
said, "We wrestle not against flesh and
blood."
>> He was he was talking about an ancient
Greek art of wrestling called the
pancration.
>> That was the name of the of the of the
fighting style. And he actually used the
art of wrestling to say, "Hey,
in the Christian realm, we wrestle not
against flesh and blood." Yes.
>> Right. our our fighting style our
pancration
>> is not against physical things but
against spiritual things.
>> So in this way
>> that's why Laya in this way
>> right
our goal is how do I think about how
many people in your past how many people
in your life were you just like they
come at me right or I didn't do anything
and this person just came at me and And
then when you begin to think in this
mindset, okay,
Lord, help me to just
>> Yeah.
>> I'mma use their I'm not going to use
your energy. I'm simply going to
redirect it.
>> And it's you're gentle,
>> right?
>> And it's not necessarily just with other
people coming at you, right? Sometimes
it's
>> a lot of times it's self coming at you,
>> right?
self is coming at you with negative
thoughts and and anger and and doubts
and frustrations.
>> Yes.
>> And we have one of two options, right?
We can either let self,
>> you know,
>> plant. We can make those thoughts and
stuff plant in our brain,
>> right? So, we can either let self karate
chop us.
>> Yeah.
>> Right.
>> And we was like, why why do they have to
scream?
>> Okay. Okay. So,
you know, and it's kind of funny because
like
>> back in that world, yeah, back in that
world,
>> there was, you know, a kung fu person
didn't look with much respect at a
karate person, right? Because, you know,
it's like east coast, west coast rap,
right? Like, it was just like, oh, they
don't know what they're doing. So, I'm
not d, you know, I'm not saying, oh, one
artist is better than the other, but
>> you are.
>> Yeah. For the kung fu person, it was
always like,
>> hey, like karate is loud, it's abrasive,
it's that's not the right way to fight,
>> right? Um,
>> it's not graceful. It's not terrible.
>> It's not graceful. It's not. So, in a in
a sense, you know, there are a lot of
there are a lot of Christians
that are like karate,
abrasive,
>> right?
>> And therefore, they're losing. Mhm.
>> Jesus was not abrasive. He was not
um he wasn't abrupt. Everything he did,
he did in a spirit of gentleness, in a
spirit of meekness. And so ultimately,
that's what we're trying to learn. Lord,
teach me how to fight
with grace
>> so that as I'm fighting, when you look
at that, you know, that taichi person
fighting, they're not putting a lot. It
just seems like there how did you just
throw the guy over there just by doing
this like you weren't like throw it was
just like
they use minimum energy
>> right they're not using energy at all
they're just like I'm just going to
redirect the energy you're throwing at
me
>> right
>> how think about how much easier your
life would be if we could redirect the
energy
>> right
>> yes
>> that redirect the energy that either
self throws at us or people throw at us
and just like
>> you're extending. They're getting worn
out,
>> right?
>> Because they're like and you're just
like
>> the gentle way. You're just flowing.
You're just flowing. That's the that's
>> the best analogy I can think of in the
in the, you know, in the regular world
>> to say this is what the spirit of
gentleness is,
>> which means no, it's not weakness. It's
it's reserving strength.
>> Reserving strength. And that's what they
do. I'm going to reserve strength and
I'm just going to utilize your your own
power against you. So if not, if they're
not initiating any strength, you have no
reason to initiate it. You know, they're
like, "Okay, you're not even fighting
me. You're not initiating." And it's but
if you come at me,
>> I'm not going to wear myself out,
>> right?
>> I'm going to let you wear yourself out
and I'm just going to redirect that
energy. And it's one of the most
powerful ways of protecting
>> the new man.
>> Melinda, I see you jumping in to I see
you.
>> I'll let one of them share and then I'll
say what I want to say. Go ahead,
Melinda.
>> Yeah. So, I wanted to um come back on
what you said about like the flow and I
think that's that's a principle that is
like
>> also going back to um making it look
effortless. And I think because you you
wrote in the um in the Sabbath school um
book that we're studying that it takes
effort to make it look effortless.
>> And I think the effortless part kind of
comes in when we get into like the flow
state. Cuz like I know when I'm studying
it takes a lot of effort as in I have to
sit down and persist in actually
studying until I get into that mental
flow state where it's just like natural.
And I think the persistence part is just
coming back and asking for the Holy
Spirit till we receive that state of
flow where we can just effortlessly with
like no energy just like redirect all
the all the negative stuff that comes at
us. I don't know. I think that that's a
really cool analogy.
>> Yes. Amen.
>> Again, a combination
of the fruits of spirit, self-control,
gentleness.
>> Yes.
>> That's right. So we're because we were
talking about earlier how really
these are nine different aspects of the
same spirit.
>> So
to have this you have to have all the
other ones as well.
>> You can't be gentle if you don't have
love. Right? So all of these work
together
and yet as we said like sometimes you
have you know well in order for me to
overcome this situation right now I need
gentleness right up front
>> right
>> right a and then I need I need patience
because if this per you might be gentle
one time
but you don't have patience the second
time it happens or the third time you're
you snap Right?
>> So, you begin to see how here's how
these here's how these these uh
manifestations of the spirit work
together.
And I
>> you need the full package of the spirit.
>> That's right.
>> The full package.
>> Don't just buy spare parts.
>> Yep. Don't buy spare parts. Very good.
Very good.
>> That is great.
>> Uh and God doesn't sell it in spare
parts, right?
>> He's not like, "Hey, I
>> He's giving us the whole thing." And and
I love what you said about the state of
flow.
>> Um there is a there is a state in which
your mind
let me say what's the best way I could
put it.
You're not thinking anymore. You're not
thinking about it anymore. It's not
you're not thinking in order to produce
the effort. It it is be it is reflexive.
>> It is reflexive. Yeah. and and man, how
how to attain that state of flow. I
might be preaching a sermon on that
because I love that title.
>> The flow.
>> The a state of flow.
>> Oh, state of flow. Okay.
>> How do you how do you get into that
state of flow where every time you
shoot, you're just hitting without
thinking? Every time you you hit, every
time you punch, every time you you
catch, every time you do it, it's almost
like
you've done it so much that you no
longer need to think about it. And
>> as they, you know, I think somebody put
in the chat, it's like practice makes
perfect, right?
>> The effort that I'm putting forward
is so that I can get to that state of
effortlessness.
>> Yep.
>> Amen.
>> And get to that state of effortless.
>> Sorry. Go ahead, Michaela. the habit
then Melinda
>> redirecting
redirecting the course of self just
redirecting that as a habit
>> I guess
>> that's right
>> yes
>> and listen you we get all the practice
in the world because if there's nobody
around to practice with you can always
shadow box
>> I'm gonna I'm gonna comment after
Melinda comments about
>> because self is always box self is
always there
>> oh yes oh yeah go ahead Melinda why
don't you share your thought and then
I'll follow up with what you're sharing.
>> I think it I kind of forgot.
>> That's okay. That's okay. When you get
it back, it'll come back to you.
>> It will come back to you. Um I was just
going to say, you know, I always have to
just
>> I we always like, yeah, if you, you
know, these are great principles. if you
know you run into somebody and they're
you know come at you sideways or you
know anything in the streets but I
always have to just bring it home
>> because that is where we get the most
practice using the fruits of the spirit
>> uh the young ladies they're not married
so they won't get this part as far as
marriage goes but they're they're
children still living in their parents'
home so as children they you know can
experience family you know dynamic and
conflict at time everybody does um and
So it's like how do we respond? How do
we get to show these fruits of the
spirit? And it is the most practical way
within our family relationships. You
know, the people who are the closest to
us
>> tend to
get on our nerves the most or you know
or you know make us you know frustrated
or whatever. Whether you're a parent,
you're dealing with your children. This
is where we are tempted the most and
where we get to practice. Like I don't
think we need to do no shadow boxing
because we
We have we have we can practice the
gentleness coming speaking to our our
children who did something wrong. They
absolutely did something wrong and they
need to be punished. We are still to
come with gentleness.
>> God is still because when we come with
gentleness and this is and going back to
what Dr. Gottman is teaching like you
actually get the result that you want.
So whatever if you come at your child
uh with gentleness or a soft startup.
You want them to understand and h and be
truly like feel bad about what they did
and you know change that behavior like
you're with the spirit of God you with
you are going to uh be able to get that
reaction from them. You're most likely
going to get that reaction. it should
come from them versus when you do a hard
start up and come at them back with
anger or uh just not with a a gentle you
know yeah the way you know if you if you
come at them back sideways or whatever
then you're going to
>> it's going to meet they're going to meet
that energy and you're not going to get
what you want and you want the heart to
change
>> and that's the way because God doesn't
come at us like yelling and screaming I
mean, he comes, the Holy Spirit comes
gently like like I was sitting in my car
when that thing happened this week and
the Holy Spirit just was like and I just
heard the thoughts and it was gentle
like turn this way. You're not thinking
right. You know what I mean? You need to
think. So, I'm just saying like we want
our children or our spouse or whoever to
think better. So, you need to come at
them with
>> um yeah,
>> that type of spirit, a gentle spirit.
>> So, I mean, think about the text again.
A soft answer. A soft answer turneth
away.
>> Everybody do this where you are right
now.
>> Sends it on your way.
>> Right. A soft answer turns away rap.
Yes.
>> Right. Just turns away. So when you have
that mental picture in your mind,
>> right? and understanding, hey, like if I
have to go speak to someone, if I have
to go address someone,
>> help me to come with gentle energy,
right?
>> Because if I come with gentle energy,
you're not you're not you're never
thinking I'm blocking a blow. You know,
if someone comes up to me and they're
like, you know, I'm not like I'm not
trying to defend myself. If they come at
me with a right or a hi, I'm I'm getting
ready to be defensive. Yeah.
>> But if I see someone coming up like,
>> you know, I'm not there's nothing in my
mind that's like get ready to defend
yourself. Get ready to defend yourself.
So we have to realize a lot of times we
you know we find ourselves in situations
because
>> we were we came with the mindset of the
karate guy versus
>> the tai chichi guy. Right.
>> I'm going to use
>> we came with the ha.
>> I'm so using this in my therapy
sessions. I'm going to use your
analogies. I just love it. I just I've
never used the martial arts, but I'm
going to use it because karate is just
like not the way you want to come at
anybody in the in relationship,
especially you if you want to be happily
married because I was just going to say
with the couples, I can see like we're
in session and I can see like when you
said like the defense like if they come
with the karate shop then you're going
to be like ah and I can see the defense
wall just rising up in the the other
spouse and it's like
>> you're not going to get what you want.
That's not how you say that. You know,
you need to be gentle. You need to come
gently. And you're like, "Oh, I don't
have to like
>> there's no The reason why people do this
is because we're you're they're afraid."
>> So, when you come with a karate chop
type of way, the spouse or the other
person, the other person you're dealing
with is going to try to protect
themselves because they feel like I'm in
danger. You're attacking me.
>> Yeah.
>> But when you're like gentle,
>> hi. You don't have to. But if I come at
you like I'm about to hit you, then
you're going to be like, "Whoa."
>> Yeah.
>> So, somebody says, "So, it man, not
Power Rangers." Exactly. For those who
know who who the who they are.
>> Um, let me say this and I'm I'm gonna
because
>> I know ladies, don't let us talk. You
guys can interrupt us anytime.
>> But I'm going to say this, right? That
when you look at two karate people
fighting, it looks violent.
>> It looks
>> I'm getting a vibe that you don't like.
You don't really but you don't really
like you did not really like that
martial art. Okay. I just I just get the
vibe.
>> So, but if you look at two chai two tai
chichi people fighting, it almost looks
>> graceful.
>> It looks like a dance.
>> H. Yes.
>> Right.
>> It's it's very everything is it looks
like they're dancing. So think about,
you know, man, would I rather would I
rather fight with my brother or sister
or dance? Hey, that argument that that
was a that was a man, how much better it
would be if we learned,
>> you understand? Yes.
>> Please, nobody take this. Pastor Mar is
saying we should dance.
>> How much better it would be, right?
>> If we should dance,
>> if our fighting looked more like a dance
>> rather than hya. Mhm.
>> Right.
>> And we're learning how to deal with deal
with each other gently
>> and nobody ends up hurt
>> because everything was gentle.
>> Everything was gentle.
>> It's beautiful.
>> Okay.
>> You know, I'm so using this. You just
don't even
>> I think I'm done with the Tai Chi
analogy.
>> I'm so using
>> My clients are going to be looking at me
like
know you knew that much about martial
arts. Go ahead. Go ahead,
>> Melinda. Something that I think is
really interesting and I don't know this
gets like really psychological but it's
really interesting how the devil has
kind of succeeded in making us think
that God is coming at us with like you
know karate and like ah
>> and we're just like and we we get like
defensive and we don't want to like
approach God because it's like oh he's
going to like I don't know hit me or
something but it's totally not true like
we've been so
blinded into thinking that that's God's
method of fighting when Jesus is clearly
just all about, you know, Tai Chi as
you're you're saying. You know what I
mean?
>> Yeah.
>> He's he's Yeah, he's really loving. He's
soft. He comes with us. So gentle. So
yeah. And it's very interesting because
um the other morning we were uh reading
the Bible
>> and uh you noticed that when Cain killed
Abel
and you didn't say in exactly this way
but you would almost think that God
would have come to Cain with karate like
>> he just committed he just killed his
brother.
>> You just did what? All right. ready.
>> I mean,
>> what does he do? He puts a mark on Cain
>> as protection. Protection for him.
>> Anyone who kills Cain is going to have
to answer to me.
>> Like, don't come at him like I'm
protecting this wretched man that just
killed his brother.
>> And you think
how God like what? But this
>> and it wasn't because he agreed with
what he did or he felt. No, of course he
God had the right to
>> he could have been like
get rid of him if he karate
>> to break him in pieces.
>> Anything,
>> right? And so when we see
>> Isn't that what he didn't do with
Lucifer as well? Like he didn't karate
chop Lucifer either.
>> That's right.
>> Some of us wish he would have.
>> He is still tai chiing Lucifer.
>> But there's
>> He is still Tai Chi Lucifer. Right.
Right?
>> He could have destroyed him a long time
ago,
>> but he is still in this very gentle way
>> allowing things to play out so that
in the end, Lucifer's own energy,
>> his everything he put forth is going to
be brought back upon his head.
>> Yes.
>> Wow.
The cross was Jesus going
>> Yes.
Yes. Oh, that's beautiful. Yes. Yes.
>> But in that in that tai chieness, if you
will, again, please understand, I'm I'm
using it as an analogy, right? In that
>> perfect analogy,
>> in that gentleness of the cross,
>> in the flow,
>> the devil the flow of the cross,
>> the devil is absolutely
defeated. Yes.
>> I mean, it's almost like, "Go ahead, hit
me." And everything that's being thrown
at Christ on the cross. I can't do it
now. But it's like, you can't hit him.
You cannot touch him on the cross.
You're He's like, "All right, hands
open,
>> you know, arms spread wide. You go ahead
and hit." And nothing lands.
>> It makes me think dodgeball. Like I used
to really like playing dodgeball and I
would get so good that I would just
challenge the people on the other side
of the line. Here, just hit me. And then
they would really try and I'd just be
like
>> and I would literally be like just like
hopping around and kind of look really
flow and they were just like so furious.
I was like, "Huh, just hit me." You
know,
>> do you know at PE It's funny that you
said that, Melinda. I loved dodgeball
when I was a kid playing you I don't
know if you played that in public. Okay.
Okay. Like Well, our little Adventist
school like couldn't wait for recess and
we would play dodgeball and that was the
funnest game. But yes, it's a great
analogy. I loved it.
>> Yeah. I think is basically like listen
as long as you're on the cross it seems
like on the cross you're exposed
>> right no fighter wants to fight like
this every fighter
>> right you're you're center you're you
know
>> you're you're bending like everything is
about protecting the body
>> but Jesus's style of fighting was this
>> and in this
>> mercy
>> everything that physically happened to
his body nothing touched his spirit Yes.
>> Mhm.
>> So, here's Satan. Here's Jesus on the
cross. And here's Satan literally like,
"You're on a I got you now."
>> Throwing every punch possible at Jesus
>> and nothing lands.
>> How embarrassing for Satan.
>> Here you have the enemy literally on a
cross. Can't move.
How are you not hitting him?
>> Right.
>> And now if we don't want to get hit,
>> when we're off the cross, we're going to
get hit every
>> The only way to not get hit.
>> Wow.
>> Stay on that cross.
>> Stay on the cross.
>> Everything will miss you.
>> Yes.
>> You
>> But it's so hard because you're going
like this and you really just want to
like protect yourself, you know? Yeah,
>> it's like this is against the whole
nature of fighting and that's all what
surrender is about. Like what battles
are won through surrender.
>> This one is but it feels so unnatural.
>> Yes.
>> The most important battle of all time in
your life is you beat it by
surrendering.
>> I want to go back to um to the Cain
story and the way God responded. It's
like we have to I know it just hit me
heavy this week, but we h that's the way
that we are supposed to respond to
people
that deserve our wrath and anger.
>> Y
>> they've even hurt us.
>> Like Cain deserved God's wrath and anger
if he wanted to pour it all out on him.
And he was like because the reason and
this is what I'm gonna say. And please
take this the right way everyone because
I know we've been wounded and hurt and
by humans and it's emotionally it's it's
very hard to go through that. But God
knew that because I was thinking about
it after we were reading it that God
knew that
Cain was going to have to live with what
he did
>> for the rest of his life. And that that
enough is punishment
to know that you harmed killed your
brother. So when it says like okay well
Cain you know and eventually had kids
and you know
>> whatever um you know still lived a whole
life but it was with that emotional
mark. So God's like, I don't have to
pour my wrath out on you. Like you know
>> what he knew what he had done. And so
even when somebody hurts you,
um definitely you guys know I teach
about boundaries and everything here.
You need to put boundaries, but you
don't have to come back at them with all
that wrath. The emotional pain that
they're going to go through for what
they have done
>> is really yeah
>> enough punishment and it stays with
them. It's much you think of like if you
bite somebody eventually the the bruises
or the that pain is going to go away but
the emotional thought that oh I hurt you
and when you really repent of that
you're always humble and meek and like
wanting to just you know make up for
what you have done but never do anything
like that again
>> to hurt that person or anyone else.
>> Yeah. And remember Cain said my
punishment is more than I can bear
>> because it was emotional. Yeah. And you
know, I mean, even thinking about Cain's
response,
>> he didn't say, "My action was more than
I can bear." He said, "My punishment is
more than I can bear."
>> Yeah.
>> Which again shows his mind is in the
wrong place.
>> Right.
>> Hey, the consequences of what I've done
is more than I can bear.
>> But he was willing to
>> he was willing to deal with killing his
brother.
>> Yeah. So you can see the spirit of Cain
ultimately in in you know the wicked at
the end of time.
>> But again look at how God dealt with
him.
>> Wow.
>> We always want to put everybody in their
place and no he didn't and no she didn't
and how
>> we can treat them with gentleness.
>> Yeah.
>> That's that's what the example God gives
us.
>> Yeah. that that situation of of all
possible scenarios that seems like a
good place to use
this idea of like
righteous anger but in a wrathful way.
>> So yeah, I guess that's God's version of
showing righteous anger. My anger is
actually love. And
>> also thinking about
Cain and the fruits of the spirit, like
we talked about how
you don't have gentleness. You don't
have the full package. You're not you're
not bearing fruit. Cain couldn't even
grow
>> grow things anymore. He couldn't um
bring fruit fruit forth from anymore.
>> So
>> yeah. And listen, remember that.
>> Wow. Yeah. Remember that he brought
fruit.
He brought fruit as the offering to God.
>> It was his own fruit.
>> And it was his own fruit.
>> And what he did was just a demonstration
of, hey, this is you offering me your
own fruit. Here's the result.
>> Here's what's in your heart. When you're
offering your own fruit, this is what's
really in your heart.
>> This is what's really in your heart.
>> Pride. Yeah.
>> When you bring your own fruit.
>> Yeah.
>> But it makes me think of works.
>> Your own fruit and works.
>> That's right.
>> And then you look at it like
>> Yeah. Because brought Abel brought the
lamb.
>> And Cain just brought not the lamb.
>> Yep.
>> He brought his own fruit that he worked
for. And that's why we're not saved by
works. And works does not get us in a
connecting relationship with God.
>> So think of it like this. works is us
uh
attempting to block the blow
with force,
right? Works is us
um putting forth
the effort when what God is saying is
listen, let me fight for you,
>> right? Let me fight for you. So,
and that let me fight for you means that
you have to obtain or you have to you
have to remain in this position,
>> right?
>> You have to remain on the cross.
>> You got to remain. This is your fighting
style right here.
>> Yes.
>> All right. Person looking at you like,
"Wait, what?
This is your fighting style? Oh, man.
I'm about to I'm about to beat you
down." And yet when you're like this,
>> and this is the thing, Jesus's body was
was bloodied and bruised up,
>> but his spirit.
>> Yes.
>> Untouched.
>> So, all right. How do I learn to start
fighting like
>> like that?
>> Like this? Because I've just I've
trained all my life, right,
>> to to get into my stance.
But the stance of the Christian,
>> don't don't think, you know, don't think
karate kid
do like this, but that and that's what
many of us do.
>> If you don't leave karate alone,
>> many of us are like, okay, all right
with the kick like, yeah, yeah, you're
not dead. You're you're you cheated just
now. The God is like, nope,
>> I want you to stay here. Your fighting
style is to stay
>> like this.
>> And if you stay like this, I promise
you,
>> I'm going to fight for you. I'm going to
defend you. Because staying like this is
saying, "All right, Lord. I trust you.
>> I trust you."
When we don't trust him, we might get up
there, but then be like, "Yo, hold on."
We're fighting with one hand and the
other on the cross like no
>> it's like it's like we're it's like
we're in a class like God has a class
and our effort is to stay in the class
and to focus on the teacher.
>> Yes.
>> But sometimes we don't we don't focus on
the teacher. We're like oh well let me
try this or let me try this. And God's
like no please focus on the teacher.
That's your effort. I'm gonna teach you
this.
>> Yep. And we're just like
>> on our own
>> because we're not we're not exercising
patience
>> and we just think like
>> and
>> yeah and that yes I mean I'm I'm
thinking of myself personally. I mean
you know that I can be like an Energizer
Bunny or think oh let me fix this or you
know what I'm saying? Sometimes I have
to just step back and be patient not
think I have to fix everything. And so
sometimes like a lot of times I mean
I've and can overstep
God. You know what I mean? You just have
to like let him do the work in you.
>> Um and not
>> go before him. And that's not having
that's not having patience and just
waiting for him to
>> and some pride there like no no I can do
this. I can fix this. No, let God let
God work.
>> So we have to get out of the way to let
him work. I think I heard that today in
the sermon too that I was listening to
this morning just talking about like God
is like, "Okay, good. You're out of the
way. Now I can really work." Because
sometimes we'd be like slowing up his
his process when we're just supposed to
be in the Yeah.
>> just chilling in faith.
>> Yeah.
>> Praying and letting him work.
>> Yeah. I kind of, you know, I'm thinking
about how Jesus described the spirit and
he said the wind bloweth where blows
where it where it wants to blow. And the
way he said it just it was it's just
like,
hey, the way the spirit works is like
you don't you can't see when it's
coming, where it's going. It's just all
it's this flow. Right.
>> Right. It's this just gentle.
>> We have our own spiritual
>> Yeah.
>> wind radar blessing.
>> It's not a hurricane.
>> I know. You can't always know where it's
>> Yeah. It's not a hurricane. It's it's
just
and that just sounds just
and you don't have to be afraid of it.
Faith over fear. You can just let it go.
Yeah. Let it come.
>> That sound right.
>> You're having so much fun with this
today because he's having a lot of fun.
I can tell you.
>> And that's it. Like
>> Yeah.
>> Lord, teach me how to just have that
And
>> it's okay. I don't know if this can if I
can pull this in, but it almost it's
almost like the breath of life. You know
what I mean?
>> Because the breath is also wind
>> and it's like let's be open to the
breath of life cuz if you just resist
it,
>> what's the point?
>> You know the what do they call it in
Hebrew? Is it ru or something
>> where it's like this is the breath of
life from God for the new creation.
>> But you have to stay focused on that.
Don't try to
do CPR on yourself. Like God's gonna end
his time. God's gonna,
>> you know what I mean?
>> Yeah.
>> She said do CPR on yourself.
>> Which is impossible, but yes, you're I
love that. I love that.
>> Yeah.
>> That's beautiful.
>> Yes. Yes. We have a few moments, but I
feel like we're right at a
>> Yeah. Perfect ending time.
>> Yeah.
>> Do you think I mean we could we could
pick up Do you think we
>> we'll pick up on the spirit of goodness
uh next week?
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> That's the next one.
>> All right.
>> So, we got through one, guys. We got
through one fully today.
>> Yeah.
>> Yes. But this has been such a blessing.
will I don't think I think the
highlights for me and I can let I'm
gonna let you guys close out too is uh
you don't want to approach anything with
the karate chop
>> the yeah don't do that and of course the
movements. So those two things are
definitely standing out for today how we
want to approach
>> any situation in our life whatever's
brought to us
>> we want to be gentle just move it out of
the way.
>> Yeah. But ladies, tell us what your
closing remarks are, if you have any.
>> Today, what stands out to me is
definitely the state of flow.
>> I know that's just a big one for me.
Yeah,
>> cuz I try to like achieve that when I'm
studying all the time. But it's also
like, oh, there's also a spiritual state
of flow.
>> You just put in that effort to stay with
it. Stay with it. Stay with it. And
eventually, you're going to get that
state of flow, and it's going to be
natural.
>> Yeah.
>> Amen.
>> Amen. Effortless.
>> Yes.
Yeah. Michaela, do you have any closing
remarks?
>> Oh, go ahead.
>> Yeah, I I definitely agree that state of
flow is something I personally really
want. And then
>> Amen. just applying that in
like every situation both in struggles I
may have internally or when I'm just
interacting with
family or
um people I'm wanting to share share the
things I'm passionate about the state of
flow really seems to apply. So
>> Amen. Amen. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> Yes. It was a blessing. Why don't you uh
for those who joined that were not here
at the beginning, let us know about your
sermon that's coming up.
>> Yeah. Okay. Uh so, first of all, thank
you guys for joining us again. Um
another
>> pray with you before we
>> beautiful uh Sabbath.
>> Um yeah, we'll pray with you before you
guys jump off. Yep.
>> Um but uh again uh for the divine
service. Um so many of you know that uh
Charlie Kirk came out with a book about
the Sabbath.
>> Um And we're not going to I mean we'll
we're going to
>> read the book before he
>> speak about the issue of the Sabbath.
>> Um also um uh Kirk Cameron
>> uh recently
um changed his position on the position
of Hellfire
>> because of his young adult son.
>> Son. Yeah.
>> Amen.
>> So we're going to be talking about those
issues, those two issues. And again,
what you're going to hear today um
will very likely I'm not going to say
100% but it it will very likely be
different from anything you have ever
heard on this subject because I'm going
to be talking about both the Sabbath and
the idea of an eternally burning hell.
And um I I think that God has uh uh
again spoken through this message in a
very powerful way. So, please let people
know that this sermon is coming up.
Please invite them to tune in. Um,
especially those who may not be familiar
with the Sabbath. Um, may not be
familiar with um with the the
understanding of of Hellfire and what
the Bible actually teaches.
>> Uh, so today is going to be a an
evangelism Sabbath, but it's not just
for people who are outside of our faith.
>> It's for all of us. And amen.
>> I pray that it will help us to see
>> both of these subjects in a way that we
have never seen before.
>> Amen. Amen. Um yes, we want to close out
with Michaela and Melinda. And somebody
was like, who are these, you know, young
ladies? These are some of our LOC youth,
uh the leaders of Friday Night Lights.
And so they are staples here on Sabbath
school as we are going through this
book. Um and so for the Christian Art of
War. So this is Elc Youth in action and
we love it. But it was a wonderful
Sabbath school guys and uh we look
forward uh to having you back next week
if their schedules match.
>> And yes,
>> I just want to say something real quick.
I know that there are some people who
are having uh some trouble commenting on
um on the YouTube feed and you know I'm
not exactly sure. I just want you to
know that we know that there is uh some
of you are unable to comment.
>> Um I'm going to suggest that you know if
you're not subscribe to the channel
first of all make sure you subscribe.
But I know that there are some of you
that that have subscribed and for some
reason cannot comment.
>> Yeah. um we're going to look into that.
So, please know that you know you're not
being blocked at all um or anything like
that. We're just I'm not exactly sure
what's going on, but we will be looking
into it. Okay.
>> Yes. Yes. All right. Um so, yes, uh
like, subscribe, and invite to the our
divine worship service and the Sabbath
sermon. You're not going to want to miss
it, and you're not going to want anyone
else to miss it either. So, please do
your part. Subscribe, like, and share.
>> Yeah.
>> All right.
>> And I'm just going to say this. I'm
always excited to preach, but you know,
when I'm doing like a doctrinal message,
I'm like, "Yeah, I've done." Listen,
>> this I'm excited to
>> even last week's sermon was fire.
>> Yeah.
>> Sorry.
>> By God's grace.
>> By God's grace. It was divine fire.
>> Um I'm really looking forward to to
sharing with you all. So, that's Yeah,
that's enough on that.
>> Okay. All right.
>> Would one of you be willing to close us
out in prayer? Yes,
>> Michaela. Or I'll do it. Okay. Thank
you.
>> Okay. Sure.
>> Thank you.
>> Um, dear heavenly father, thank you that
we're able to study um your gentleness
today.
with that and help us to
um really focus on this state of flow
and
um
>> Amen.
>> Amen. Sorry, but we Sorry got muffled
there a little.
>> Yeah, we did. We didn't say amen. That's
okay. We stayed in a little bit longer
moment of prayer. It's fine.
>> All right, guys. Thank you. And we will
see you next week by God's grace. And
for the rest of you,
>> yes, happy Sabbath. For the rest of you,
we'll see you in the divine worship
service. Don't forget to like,
subscribe, and share. See you there.
We're here in St. George's Town in the
beautiful island of Bermuda, walking
down Church Lane. Here lies the remains
of a pictures structure known as the
unfinished church. Let's go check it
out.
This elegant edifice is notable for its
Gothic architecture, open ceilings, and
grass carpeted ground. The construction
of this church began in the late 1800s,
but it was never finished due to various
natural, financial, and social
obstacles. Today, it's used for outdoor
weddings, parties, and various other
community events. With the sky for its
ceiling and the grass for its carpeting,
it's definitely an amazing sight to
behold.
But far more amazing is the spiritual
lesson it teaches. You see, just as the
original architect had a finished
product in mind when drawing the plans
for this structure, so too the divine
architect has a completed work in mind
for the human race. The church of God is
not some building made of wood, brick,
stone, or mortar. It's not some literal
building that's going to be rebuilt in
Jerusalem or anywhere else. But rather
God's church is his living, breathing
saints. That's you and me. We are the
temple of God and the church of the
living Christ. A gathering of those who
have been called out of darkness and
into his marvelous light.
And the divine architect is not finished
with us. He desires to build us up into
his likeness and loveliness. But
unfortunately, sin has interrupted and
corrupted God's building project. The
walls of our morality have been
contaminated by the base elements of
this world. Satan's birds have found
lodgement in the cracks and crevices of
our lives. Weeds have grown on our
foundation and the windows of our soul
have been broken. What a pitiful sight
is the natural state of man. We are
undone, unfinished, and uninhabitable.
But the master carpenter still has the
blueprint for a finished work in us. God
desires to live in us so that he can
shine through us into all the world. The
pen of inspiration writes, "Through the
agency of the Holy Spirit, God desires
that his image shall be restored in
humanity, that a new and living
principle of life shall be introduced
into the minds that have become defiled
by sin. The love of God is fully able to
restore, rebuild, encourage, and
strengthen every believing soul who will
accept the truth as it is in Jesus. God
has all the power and the resources to
finish his work in us. The only thing he
lacks is the building permit. He will
not force himself on us. The building
permit is ours to give or it's ours to
keep. Now, if you know anything about
acquiring a permit to build, it usually
requires two things. An expensive fee to
be paid and then a long duration of
waiting for approval. Only then can the
work begin and thus be brought to
completion. And when it comes to the
unfinished church of humanity, there's
good news and bad news. The good news is
that Christ has already paid in full the
price for the building permit. Not with
corruptible things like silver or gold,
but with the gold of his blood and the
silver of his tears. But here's the bad
news. Christ is waiting for the building
permit to be approved. He's still
waiting for us to give him permission to
work in our hearts, to allow him to lay
a solid foundation of faith in our
hearts and our homes and our eyes to
surround us with the sturdy walls of his
law and to cover us with the sheltering
roof of his righteousness. Though the
price has already been paid in full,
humanity stubbornly withholds the
building permit.
And tragically, as the completion
deadline of Jesus return is almost come,
many are still unfinished and unready.
This unfinished church on Church F Lane
had a beginning, but no ending. My
friend, please don't be like this. When
the Lord returns, you don't want to be
like the unfinished church on Church Fod
Lane. You want to be the glorious church
bringing holy joy to your master and
maker. God is strong enough to finish
what he has started in your life. The
question is, are you willing enough to
give him the permission to do it? Don't
withhold from Jesus the building permit.
Give to him the building permit of your
life. And only then will you be finished
and complete.
We hope you've been blessed and inspired
by this new Reflections of Hope episode.
This episode is one of many that's been
produced all over the world. If you
haven't done so yet, please give our
video a like, share it with your
friends, and please follow us on
Instagram, Facebook, and YouTube. If
you'd like to see more inspiring
episodes and get access to much more
uplifting content, please go now to
patreon.com/revelationof
hope and sign up to be a member of our
Patreon page. Your monthly support will
not only give you early access to many
more inspiring videos, but it will also
enable us to continue to produce more of
these cinematic object lessons from
nature. Our goal is to produce and
release these episodes much more
frequently. So, please prayerfully
consider partnering with us so that we
may continue to share the hope of Jesus
all over the world. Thank you so much
for your support. Aloha and Marinata.
Heat. Heat.
Heat.
Welcome back, Living Mana Church family.
So good to see you here. And for some of
you, we're so happy that you decided to
continue to worship with us. We are just
so happy that it's the Sabbath and we
get to fellowship with all of you from
all around the world. If this is your
first time or if you haven't done so
yet, please uh like and subscribe to the
YouTube channel that you are on. Um, we
just want to reach as many people as we
can and let them know that we're here,
what our subject is about uh today for
the the sermon, and just for them to
come and be blessed and to worship with
us and get all the blessings that we
have uh during this church service
today, what God has for all of us during
this church service today. So again,
welcome. We're so happy that you are
here. Please put in the chat. If this is
your very first time, put a one in the
chat and let us know where you are
viewing from. And for the rest of you,
we just want to say welcome to you too.
So, please put where you are viewing
from. And again, we just want to wish
you a big happy Sabbath today. So, I
don't know about you, but for those who
have been watching uh viewing with us
all day, Sabbath school was a blessing.
It was a blessing for for me to to hear
the different things that everyone had
to share. where God was really speaking
through our young people uh today and
the things that Pastor Meyers shared. It
was truly truly a blessing. So, if you
didn't get to see it, go back and see
it. We're still doing the Christian Art
of War. Um and this is a book that
Pastor Meyers uh wrote over about 15
years ago. Um and so we are going
through it just chapter by chapter and
we're getting through it. We're getting
through it, but we're moving through it
very slowly because there's so much
there uh that we can all benefit from.
So, okay. I see. Let's see. I want to
say happy Sabbath and welcome to um Oh,
boy. It went up so fast, but I think it
was South Carolina. Uh, it went up so
fast. Yes, there it goes. Um, and so,
yeah, I just want to say welcome um to
you there in South Carolina. Also, we
have Ham in Louisiana. Welcome. Good to
see you here. Uh again I see see someone
from my from my state my home state from
oh that's Maria of course our sister Dr.
Maria Humel who is the host uh one of
the host of True Health Tuesdays. But
yes, good to see you uh Maria from
California. Always good to see you and
having you here with us. want you guys
to know that if you're not watching True
Health Tuesdays, you are missing a
blessing here at Living Man Church
because uh we have some wonderful
doctors um and nutritionists and just
the God has just blessed us with some
amazing hosts for True Health Tuesdays
and giving us some great information
about our physical health. So you want
to tune in but want to say welcome um to
it says women of God for life. All
right. Happy Sabbath from Oklahoma. Good
to see you here again. Good to see our
friend here from Uganda. Good to see you
here uh with us and worshiping with us
today. We have Indianapolis, Indiana.
Good to see you here. I think it's
Tamara. Welcome. Good to see you. Such a
blessing to have all of you from so many
different um parts of the world. It is
really wonderful to see so many u
countries and then here in the in the
states so many different states. I just
want to tell you guys how you can stay
connected to living mana church. If you
are here in America in the North America
you will be able to get text alerts. And
so this is to help you have to hear get
any announcements that living out of
church is putting out but also so that
you can be reminded about when we're
going live the programming. So, like for
Mondays and mental health Monday and
yes, we have a new mental health Monday
this week. We're going to be live. So,
join Dr. Ricardo White and myself. And
um if you if you want to be reminded of
our programming like mental health
Monday, like True Health Tuesday
um on like our prayer services, our
church services, everything we do here.
If you sign up to get a text alert, it
will tell you when we're about to go
live 20 minutes before we go live, so
that you'll be reminded, especially in
our busy life, but extra especially if
you will, uh during this time of year in
the season. We know there's a lot of
hustle and bustle and working and
getting presents and spending time
preparing for family. When Christmas
does come, we're just all very busy. So,
if that busy schedule sounds like you,
you're going to want to sign up to get
text alerts so that you can be reminded
of all the amazing programming that God
uh has put together and inspired here at
Living Manage Church. So, that works if
you are here in America. But if you are
not in America, which I already told you
guys, those who are visiting for the
first time, we are an international
church. So, the international um viewing
audience and membership, they cannot get
those text alerts. So the way you get
informed and your information along with
even if you're here in North America,
everybody needs to sign up for mighty
networks because it is our virtual
church home. This is how uh you can stay
connected if you are in another country
because everyone can join mighty
networks and you'll get the
announcements. You'll be able to uh join
a community a small group what interests
you. you get to meet you get to make
some friends on Mighty Network and to
just meet the other uh viewing audience
and members of Living Mana Church. So
the link for Mighty Networks is in the
chat. So please check that out and sign
up for Mighty Networks. You're not going
to regret that. Again, the small groups
leadership is there and you get to this
is where our community is formed here on
Living Mana Church. So that is um how
you sign up for mighty networks and to
get text alerts and that's how uh you
are able to stay connected and how we're
able to stay connected with you as well.
Want you guys to know that uh we do have
children's programming and that's LOC
kids. Lamoc kids is every Saturday uh
morning cit central standard time at
11:30 and they go for about an hour and
a half and we have amazing leadership
who is teaching our kids and they're
teaching our kids uh the deep things of
God's word. So it they're they're
they're doing crafts, they're doing
music, they're learning at their age
level, but they are learning things and
even photo theology things that Pastor
Myers is teaching, they are learning
about the sanctuary, all of those
things. So this is our children's
programming is not um just a babysitting
service if you will. It is to really
teach them about God and his word and
the children really enjoy it and we have
wonderful leaders that are helping to
teach the children. So if you want your
child to get involved uh you can send an
email to the email there that you see
see on your screen the lc kidsid
livingmana.urch.
You can also just text kids to that 855
number and you will be able to get
information uh and the leadership will
be able to sign you up or sign your
child up. And even if it's not your
child and if you want to share with uh
with your sister or brother about maybe
your niece or your nephew or just any
young person that would you think would
benefit from being a part of LMLC kids,
definitely share that information uh
with them so that they can be a part of
that.
All right. So, we also want to just let
you know about Pastor Meyer's virtual
office hours that you can um send uh
Patrice at living.live
uh an email and she will set up that
virtual office hour or he or that
virtual meeting I should say with you so
you can meet and talk with the pastor.
Also um if you are um wanting to know
about Hangouts which uh we want you to
uh be a part of Hangouts and Hangouts
has a special uh event that is happening
and that is tomorrow but for to let you
guys know about Hangouts is exactly what
it sounds like. You know we're a virtual
church but that doesn't mean we still
can't hang out. We can still hang out
and have fun. As you can see there on
the flyer, there'll be ice breakers,
trivia games, all types of things. But
let me tell you a little bit more in
detail about what tomorrow's hangout is
going to be like. And yes, pastor and I
um have attended um several of the
hangouts and we plan to be there
tomorrow as well. So come out and hang
with us. Okay. But it's tomorrow, se
Sunday, December 14th, and the hangouts
is hosting a first ever December to
remember. We're going to test our
knowledge of some of Pastor Meyer's most
memorable sermons from 2025 with some
friendly trivia. Let's see if he even
remembers all the sermons he preached in
2025. This is going to be good. And our
hangout hosts have something special
planned, but you'll have to wait and
see. In Hangouts fashion, it will be a
night of fun and fellowship. So, so mark
your calendars. That's just tomorrow,
guys. December 14th at 5:30 p.m. Central
Standard Time. You can also text hangout
to the 855207-4107
for uh more updates if you need any
updates. So that and actually when you
sign up for that you're going to get a
reminder when we're starting. So you
don't want to miss hangouts tomorrow.
Also want to remind you guys some of you
want to know more about uh membership
how you become a member of Living Mana
Church. You can do that. That email that
you see patrice livinga.live live is the
email you would use for all three of the
of these ways that you can become a
member. The first one is if you are
already a member at an at a sister 7th
Day Adventist Church anywhere in the
world, um you can transfer your
membership to Living Mana Church if
that's what you if you would like to
become a member here. The second way to
become a member is if you are already
baptized and you're a Christian, but
you've learned so much about what the
Bible teaches and the Seventh Day
Adventist Church is in line with what
the Bible is teaching and you want to
become a member, you can join by
profession of faith. You don't have to
actually be rebaptized if that is not
needed. Uh the third way is you can be
baptized to become a member of the
living mana church and you're joining
the 7th day Adventist faith and family
that are all around the world and um
you'll be able to get baptized and
pastor Myers will baptize you and um you
can send if you want to get baptized
Patrice is the person who will get the
first email from you and contacts. So
that that email that you're seeing on
your screen is the email that you can
use for that as well. So those are the
three ways that you can become a member
of the living mana church. Also just
wanted to uh remind you guys about the
power line which is so powerful because
uh it's one of our prayer uh ministries
that we do on Wednesdays and it's its
own YouTube program and it's the power
line. We just pray. So you have two
hosts that are taking your prayer
requests live. You can share this with
anybody you know that's you know asks
you to pray and say hey do you want to
come to uh a prayer program that is is
is live and if we put your prayer
request in they will pray over you right
then and there. So, it's a great way to
introduce people to prayer if they are
not that familiar with the power of
prayer. And it's a great way to
introduce them to the Seventh Day
Adventist Church and also to Living Mana
uh Church because they will see here we
are praying for them when they ask uh
for prayer. So, the power line as you
can see there on your screen is 8:00 PM
uh central time on Wednesday after power
Wednesdays uh programming. And so we
have again two programs on Wednesday
that are doing prayer. So you don't want
to you don't want to miss that. Also
wanted to tell you about gems and you
guys are familiar with gems but gems is
you can see what it stands for right
there. Golden aers emerging into mature
saints. That's what it stands for. So I
just want to tell you a little bit more
about gems. Gems is a welcoming
community. They're they are a welcoming
community where seasoned mature
Christians come alongside new beginners
um and offer guidance, encouragement and
spiritual support. This group creates a
safe
All right, guys. It it receives Okay,
here we go. This group create creates a
safe space to ask questions, grow in
faith, and learn practical ways to walk
with Christ every day through
conversation, membership, and shared
wisdom. Gyms helps new believers build a
strong foundation while giving senior
Christians a meaningful way to pour into
the next generation of disciples its
fellowship, growth, and spiritual family
all in one place. And I think it's just
so beautiful that God put it on the
heart of like what they like to say uh
golden aers or seasoned Christians to
want to pour into others and just be
alongside in a loving, kind, nurturing
way. So if you would like to uh join
gyms, you can see you can text gems to
that 855 number so you can be a part of
uh this small group. also want you to
know that gyms also host adult Sabbath
school. Kick off the Sabbath with fun um
engaging walk through the quarterly.
Gyms brings the lesson to life with
fresh insight, interactive discussion,
and creative ways to explore the word.
Whether you're a regular, a brand new,
or brand new, everyone is welcome to
join the conversation and start the
Sabbath with community, learning, and
joy. Here's inspiring um hope centered
copy for star. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. All right. I think Okay, here
we go. Okay, let's see. Let's go back
here. Steps to it. Okay. All right.
That's gems. I'm sorry. My my my copy
was going over each other. But
definitely join gems. Uh they do do the
traditional Sabbath school quarterly. So
you see here uh we do something
different on uh Sabbath uh when we start
the programming but then they do the
quarterly that everyone is studying from
all around the world. So if you would
like to do that then gems is definitely
for you and you can go get more
information about gems by going to
mighty networks. All right now star
steps to addiction recovery.
This is also a small group, but STAR is
a safe, judgment-free space for anyone
seeking hope, healing, and a fresh
start. This group is built on
encouragement, community, and the belief
that no one should walk this journey of
recovery alone. Whether you are taking
your first step or rebuilding after many
steps, STAR offers support,
understanding, and a place to grow at
your own pace through honest
conversation, shared experiences, and
uplifting guidance. STAR helps
individuals discover strength,
resilience, and the possibility of a new
beginning. Every meeting is an
opportunity to connect with people who
care, listen, and walk beside you. If
you're looking for a place where you can
breathe, be heard, and move forward with
support, STAR is here for you. Come as
you are come um as you are. Hope grows
here. So, STAR is an amazing small group
that if um you are needing support and
an addiction recovery support, this
small group is for you. It truly um is a
blessing. And as you can see there on
your screen, it's Sunday at 11 Central
Standard Time. And you can also text
star to that 855 number to get uh more
information about this small group. Want
to also remind you guys about Living
Mana Global. And Living Mana Global is
just what it sounds like except we are
we are global right now. We're on the
internet. So, we are all around the
world, but we want to go into the world
in the languages of the world. And so,
right now, we're able to do that in
seven different languages. And we're
going to give you a sneak peek at what
that looks like.
for
stress ketchup.
Stress
youch.
That was so cool, guys. I was speaking
Korean. That's the first time I've ever
seen myself doing something like that.
It's usually Pastor Myers, but that was
really cool. I was speaking Korean.
Somebody thought I was speaking
Mandarin. I mean, I really couldn't if
they didn't put the flag up there what
it was. I wouldn't know what I was
speaking. But, uh, yeah, that is really
cool. And that's what, uh, Living Mana
Global allows us to do is to be able to
share what we're doing here on Living
Mana, uh, each and every week in
English. were able to take the same
content um in the languages of other
people around the world and be able to
speak uh speak it in their language. And
so that's amazing. And if you would like
to continue to support uh living mana
global, I want to let you know how you
can do that. Uh we have
adventistgiving.org.
This is where you're able to give your
tithe and your offering. Um, you can
just put in Living Mana Church. Go in
the right hand corner uh to log in and
to put the church that you want to uh
support and you would put in Living Mana
Church and there you'll be able to give
your tithe which goes to support the
Northeastern Conference. Living Mana
Church is uh a church within the
Northeastern Conference. And then you
can see a place there that will say
local church budget and that's what
stays with Living Mana Church. And
within there, you're going to see so
many different areas that you can uh
support uh what we're doing here at
Living Mana Church, like Living Mana
Global. Um you'll also see
um you'll see so many different things
there, but there's areas where you can
give that helps us to be able to support
people when they are um in need. So,
you'll you'll click on the benevolence
fund and that's how you can can give
there to be able to support and other
things. And so this is how you're able
to give and to support Living Mana
Church virtually. But if that's not what
you want to do, you would like to mail
in um an offering uh or tithe, you can
do that as well. And you can send that
to the address that you can see there on
your screen. That's PO Box 428, Owens
Crossroads, Alabama 35763.
So, those are the two ways that you can
give um to be able to support the church
and by your by your tithe and by your
offering. But we also request that you
continue to pray for Living Mana Church.
That is the way that uh you can support
us and to keep us going and you have
been so faithful at both. I mean, the
giving has been there and the prayers
have definitely been there and we are so
thank you. We are so thank you. We thank
you and we're so welcome. Goodness, I
can't talk today, guys. We are so
grateful for all of your love and
support. We we are we are grateful for
everything that you have done through
your prayers, through your financial
giving. Um and we just ask that you
continue to pray for Living Mana Church.
I always let you guys know where we are
at in the timeline, but uh we are almost
at a year and a half in April. We a year
and a half, guys. I really can't talk
today. We are almost four years old in
April. Oh my goodness. We are at three
and a half years. That's what I meant to
say. Uh you know this is live, right?
This is not pre-scripted and I don't
have a teleprompter. So I just it's all
on the top of my head. Okay. All right.
But we are very just thankful to you and
for what you have done through your
prayers, through your financial gifts,
by telling people about Living Mana
Church. Um and you share the link and
all of those things help to grow the
church. Um, and so we just want to say
thank you again. And I just want to
invite you guys to pray with me as we
give God the ultimate thanksgiving. Um,
because just giving him a prayer of
thanksgiving because he does so much for
each and every one of us. So, if you
would just bow your heads with me as we
pray.
Heavenly Father, Lord, I want to thank
you. Uh, none of us are perfect, Lord.
Can't always say everything perfect.
We're real here at Living Matted Church.
But God, you are perfect and you do do
everything perfect, say everything
perfect. You minister to us in a very
perfect way, Lord, because you are
perfection. And um God, I just thank you
for all that you've done for me
personally this week, Lord. I I just
want to praise you for that. The way the
Holy Spirit just comes and ministers to
us when we're a little down or just kind
of frustrated or not understanding, you
do that for all of us. But I can testify
to that this week. you did that for me
in a mighty way. And I just want to get
just give you praise for that, Lord. I
know there's so many other testimonies
from every viewing audience um that is
watching that they could they have
something to be thankful for today,
Lord. And I want them to even think
about it because maybe they're having a
bad day. Maybe they're just not feeling
like praising you the way I just did
because they're not seeing things
happening. But that's what faith is.
Lord, we praise you anyways. We praise
you when we don't see it. We praise you
when we do see it. And that is where our
joy and our peace come from because
we're praising by faith even when we
don't see it, Lord. So, I pray for those
who I want to pray just for those people
today. I'm I'm praying for those who
don't see it, who they don't see it in
their marriage, and they don't see it in
the way they're what their children are
deciding to do. They don't see it in
their finances right now. They don't
even see it in their health situation.
Lord, I want them to praise you. I'm
asking that they praise you and have
faith that you are working in their
situation and you're going to work
things out according to your will in
your time, Lord. And the reason why um
you're asking for them to praise you
even right now in this time where you
they cannot see is because again that's
where our peace comes from. That is
where we can feel your closeness. You're
so you feel you so closely when we're in
those type of situations. So Lord, I'm
praying for everyone that's in that
situation and dealing with those issues
um in their life right now. And Lord, I
just want to um pray and ask you to be
with Pastor Meyers. I pray that the Holy
Spirit would fill him. He's so excited
about this message and I'm excited to
hear and I know we all are to see what
how what you're going to share with us
today, Lord, through him. Just help us
uh to grow closer to you in Jesus name.
Amen.
Jesus is coming. The season of Advent is
here. The season of peace.
Today I bless you with peace.
May your hearts and homes be stilled
with the deep calm,
with the presence of the king. The king
who holds the whole universe in his
hands and yet cares deeply about the
tiniest details in your life.
So let your worries go. Pause the hustle
and bustle of Christmas.
May you be filled fully with his peace
right now.
Peace that passes understanding.
It stills the storm with just one
whisper of his voice. May it settle deep
in your heart, drawing you to join the
song of the angels, singing, "Glory to
God in the highest and on earth peace
and good will for all men.
Be blessed with peace this Advent.
angels sing.
Glory to the newborn king.
The handful prince of peace
of righteous
the herald angels sing glory to the
newborn King, peace on earth and mercy
bound. God and sin reconiled.
>> Joyful
nations rise. Join the triost
proclaim.
Christ is born in Bethlehem.
The herald angels sing. Glory to the new
Lord.
the newborn
king.
Haven
prince of peace. Hail the son of
righteousness.
>> He brings with
his wings.
He lays his glory.
Born
may die. Born to raise the sons of
earth. Born to give them second birth.
Hark the herald angels sing. Glory to
the newborn
king.
The newborn
The new born
here.
Hel
the newborn.
Not the angels
sing
the newborn.
The newborn
Here at Living Mana, we bear each
other's burdens. When you need support
or prayer, when you're feeling
discouraged
or alone or anxious,
you don't have to face life struggles
alone.
Let us come boldly unto the throne of
grace that we may obtain mercy and find
grace to help in our time of need.
The Lord is close to the brokenhearted
and saves those who are crushed in
spirit.
Here at Living Mana, we bear each
other's burdens. When you need support
or prayer, when you're feeling
discouraged
or alone or anxious,
you don't have to face life struggles
alone.
Let us come boldly unto the throne of
grace that we may obtain mercy and find
grace to help in our time of need.
The Lord is close to the brokenhearted
and saves those who are crushed in
spirit.
Greetings saints, most high God. Welcome
to the prayer session. So lovely and
blessed to be here with you today. I
pray uh pray that you can hear us and
see us. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> Amen. I'm Danny Clark. I'm here with my
lovely bride, Jacqueline Clark, and
we'll be here today uh uh lifting up
prayers and praying for you and and also
just giving thanks to the to the most
high God. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> Yeah. We are filling in for brother
Terry and sister Amra, our servant
leaders. And uh what a beautiful couple.
And we always miss them, you know, but
God is always blessing them and using
them to bless others. And so we do want
to pray God's uh protection and covering
over them today as well as just, you
know, just
>> yeah,
>> you know, they're having a blessed
Sabbath, right? And experiencing the
goodness of God, but most importantly,
being able to bask in the actual
presence of God.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> Continue to be blessed, my sister. So
good to see her back on camera. She
She's looking well.
>> She's looking beautiful.
>> God is good.
>> Continue to be blessed, my sister. Amen.
>> Yes. Thank you tech team and all of you
wonderful people behind the scenes and
all that you do. Amen.
>> Makes our job easier. Trust me.
>> That's right.
>> Amen.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> And you know we have our prayer warriors
active today. Let me I just don't want
to let me just
using my other computer and we just want
to shout out to them. Brother Kashie, I
know is active in our uh
>> Yes, brother.
>> Living mana
in the living mana um uh chat channel.
Um he and sister Joanne, we have the
prayer encourager there. And then we
have sister Ayana and others that's on
the power of the lamb.
>> Yes.
>> Um giving up prayers and encouragement
>> as well as we do have prayer warriors
that's collecting prayers. So, I just
want you to know we we um we may not
have collected all prayers
um um to pray over today, but I want to
assure you uh that our prayer team is
collecting all prayers and we continue
to pray over these repair requests
through the week. Praise God. What a
beautiful ministry. And it is just it is
just wonderful to be able to
just pray over not just pray over I feel
like we're praying with
>> amen fighting with you in this fight of
faith through the challenges and
struggles that many of you are going
through. So it is a privilege
>> to be able to pray over your requests
and I want you to I would encourage you
to continue to send us those requests as
well as the praise reports.
Please send us those praise reports. If
there's anything about that praise
report you want us to omit or you know
please let us know or just rather just
send that praise report exactly how you
would like for us to give it. And I just
want to express the importance of that
praise report. You never know who's
going through the same things that you
have gone through. So it's wonderful.
It's a first of all it's a blessing to
God. It's just, you know, giving him
honor and praise and acknowledging what
God has done on your behalf. And at the
same time, you could be encouraging
someone else who's going through the
like thing or similar things. So, please
send us those praise reports. We want
everyone everyone to know what God is
doing because God is still doing great
and marvelous things. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen. I just uh want to add to
that. Just as you were speaking, I was
thinking of of these prayer warriors as
you continue to lift them up and thank
God for man, it's these these these
warriors and prayer ministers. We I'm
beginning to call them now. They're
faithful. Amen. They're faithful and and
I just got to give a shout out. You
know, we we keep them lifted up. We pray
for them. There are the We have a
24-hour prayer cast where we pray
specifically
>> specifically for our prayer warriors in
their need. And I tell you, this last
session was powerful.
>> It was
>> It was powerful, wasn't it?
>> Oh, yes.
>> Every step, every fa every session built
up on the other and and it was a
blessing. Yes. Let me tell you
something. It's it's uh it's it's
amazing.
>> Yeah. We did a 24hour
and we are we're we're awake. We're
and I'm going tell you so many people we
started at uh 6:00 p.m. well after 6:00
p.m. last Saturday all the way to Sunday
6:00 p.m. And I just have to give this
praise.
>> Our dear, you know, Sister Bal has been
out, you know, with some, you know, with
some um
>> with some health challenges. But
>> Sister Bal, she was with us just the
entire time, wasn't she? And she said
she gave a great testimony. Not only
that, but she led out in a 4-hour
session where we had we were looking at
obedience. We were looking at at a life
of of the sin of prayerlessness, the
need for forgiveness in our lives,
forgiving others. So much that we need,
you know, as as a prayer team because as
the song say, we don't want anything
between our soul and our savior, right?
Amen. But sister Val says she it has
been over 20 years. I think she said 20
years since she's able since she's been
physically able to stay up as long. And
that was a praise.
>> That was amazing.
>> Oh, that was a praise. So praise God for
that. And I want you to praise. You know
in the chats I want you to praise. Let
me tell you something.
>> When God moves, we're to praise thanking
him for what he has done. This was this
was significant for s for us. You know,
because sister Val had been out for a
while and a significant testimony for
sister Val on the goodness of God.
>> She had, you know, she started feeling a
little pain and I tell you the prayer
warriors went to praying for her and
praise God for that. But there was so
many of our prayer warriors that that
were awake leading out on that session.
So we just we that's a huge praise
report. We want to thank God for giving
us the strength and this is about
praying over our prayer warriors. A
24-hour prayer and fasting over them and
their families, their ministries because
they spend all month uh ministering to
you in our chats on our pray Wednesdays
on our power line. So we want to hold we
want to cover them up. Hold them up
before the bloodstaining banner. Praise
God.
>> It's a beautiful thing and we say that
to this to look at this how serious we
are about prayer.
>> Yeah.
>> The power of prayer.
>> Amen.
>> Many of them pressed in while they were
ailing through through headaches and
being in pain. Uh not only Sister Barl,
several sisters.
>> Yes. Sister Joanne. Joanne. Sister. It
was
>> and many of them pressing their way in
and watching the hand of God move and
bless them. So we here they are battle
ready saints. That's what we we're
serious about prayer. Amen. And as we go
through the throne of grace today, we're
in the same mode. We're ready for
battle. We're lifting your name. We're
supplicating for you. We're pleading
God, declaring and decreeing in all of
his words and his ways. Amen. Amen. Our
day started off strong. We had a strong
pre-huddle today. Amen.
>> What a blessing that was. Amen.
>> And Sabbath school. Oh, those young
ladies are awesome.
>> Amen. Beautiful. We love to see the
young people, too.
>> Young people,
>> sister Dante and pastor were awesome.
But I tell you,
>> they were they were.
>> Yeah. To see these strong young people.
This is what the world need to see
today. We don't see as much anymore, you
know. But oh my, it's just wonderful,
isn't it? It
>> is beautiful.
>> Amen.
>> Amen. And I just do want to remind you
to send your prayer request to you can
send an email to praymanana.live
if you want to send us a prayer request
as well as a praise report and you can
text pray at 8552074107.
I also want to remind you of uh our
power line. It's every Wednesday night.
>> Yeah.
>> At 8:00 pm right here. And we want to
encourage, you know, this can be a very
challenging and difficult time for
people. You may know someone on your
job. You may know someone in your
community. It doesn't matter what type
of religious uh affiliation they have or
if they have none. Doesn't matter.
>> Amen.
>> Encourage them. Give them information on
how to come to the power line, the
prayer line, the power, which is the
power line on Wednesday nights at 8
o'clock. You know, there may be some
that experience hopelessness,
loneliness, depression, and anxiety.
This is a very, this season can be very
challenging for those that don't have
family, that are feeling lost and all
alone. I encourage you, send them to
this power line so that we can pray for
them, so that we can get to know them.
We want them to know that God has given
us a mission for all people, for all
people, and that is the mission of
prayer. the hold of his people before
the bloodstained banner uh before our
prince Emmanuel. Because when we pray,
it gives God an opportunity to work in
and behalf of their lives and their
situations, we could be very well
praying for those that may not even be
praying for themselves. So, but and and
even if they're not so that if they're
not praying for themselves, when we go
to pray for them, it gives God an
opportunity to move.
>> Amen. Be sure and hit that like,
subscribe, and share.
>> Amen. Amen. Amen. Let's share this now.
>> Amen. And should I give the praise
reports?
>> Go for it.
>> All right. All right.
>> Oh my goodness. Um and then we have a
praise report for Maryanne weeks. She
says, "I am praising God for answering
my prayer request. I was anxietyfree
this past week. Happy Sabbath to
everyone. Please continue praying for
me. I wanted to make sure I get I give
the uh God the praise." Hallelujah.
Exactly. We want to make sure we give
God the praise. So, praise God and thank
you, Lord. And we're going to continue
to pray for you, Maryanne. And we got
another praise report from Christie. Uh
Christie says, she said, "Thanks for all
who prayed for traveling mercies for my
family last week. We had to flee
Michigan a day early due to the big
snowstorm that was coming in. God was
with us and others. May he bless the
emergency workers." Amen. Praise God.
Yes, we have a praise report from sister
Angela. She got a little perturred.
The the delivery man, the package
deliver the delivery person took a very
important package to the wrong address.
He just happened to add the coordinates
the coordinates to show he delivered it.
And uh she she researched the
coordinates and found out where the
package was left. It was at a boat at uh
at boat museum 22 22 miles away. And
then her prayer request, please pray in
agreement for refund, favor, or the
package to me. I'm going to call the
boat mazim in the morning. So the praise
report came. Come on, warriors. I was
just on the phone with the boat museum
manager. As soon as we hung up, my
doorbell rang. I just opened my door.
There was nobody in the hallway. Only my
package at the door. Glory be to God.
Did the mighty angels bring my package?
I'm so happy, Lord. Thank you. And thank
you prayer warriors for praying. Praise
God. And you know that was important.
That was an important package and we
didn't want to delay. So praise God.
Just one day, the very next day after
putting this uh putting this in prayer,
sending it up to the throne room, sister
Ann had an answer. Praise God.
>> Amen.
>> Sister Annette had asked us to pray for
brothers and sisters. Well, she had
asked her to pray. Um, you know, they
were going live on the YouTube power
line and she uh
maybe feeling a little anxious, but
here's a praise report. She said, "Thank
you all for your prayers. God is so
good." Yes, he is.
And he came through for us in the power
line tonight. Thank you, heavenly
father. Praise God. Thank you, Lord.
Thank you. Yes. Ain't that beautiful?
Thanking you, God. Thank you for our
praying, for our prayer. We do it once a
month at the beginning of the month,
that 24-hour prayer. But thank you,
Lord, for oh, for visiting your people,
for answering these many prayers. Thank
God, just letting your people know that
you care. Amen.
>> That you were there watching over us. We
thank you, Father, for all that you do.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> Praise God. That's those are the praise
reports. Yeah.
>> Amen. Amen. God is good.
>> God is good all the time. And all the
time, God is good.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> We're getting ready to go to the throne
of grace. I have a few prayer requests
and I think you have some too.
>> I do.
>> I will pray for the ones I have and my
lovely wife will pray for the one she
have. I'm going to tell you, let's be in
agreement as we go to the throne of
grace. Like my wife mentioned earlier,
this is a season and a time of the year
where things are pretty
can be pretty tough.
>> Yeah, they can be pretty tough as well
as dangerous. Israel is dangerous.
>> Israel is dangerous.
>> And even even this season, we're talking
about her packages and this and that
packages. I mean, they don't get shipped
on time and whatever the importance may
be and all of that frustration, just
everyday life.
>> Amen.
>> And just dealing with a season. Yeah.
>> No matter what the reason is. Yeah. You
know.
>> Yeah. And you know, you were you talking
about the seasons, all types of things
can go on. scams, schemes,
>> oh
>> um
>> even just I mean just just all even even
violent activity. So we want to cover
God's people.
>> We want to ask favor upon God's people.
We want God in asking God for his
protection to keep them from all from
danger. You know, people are stealing
and I mean this is just that time of
year when anything is is can come up.
But we just want to make sure and we
will we're going to cover everyone in
prayer.
>> Amen.
>> Amen. Amen. All righty.
>> Should I go first or did you want to go
first?
>> Um,
go ahead. Go ahead.
>> Well, brother Danny collected he
collected the power the prayer report
the prayer the prayer requests coming in
on power of the lamb and I collected
them on uh the living man on YouTube.
So, you know, he'll So, I'm going to get
started then that way he can um close
out and he'll pray for pastor too in his
prayer.
>> Amen.
>> All right. I'm just going to first go
over the request and then just uh uh say
a prayer over them. We had a prayer
request from Rain Egan. God is
wonderful. Hello family. If anyone sees
this, I'm asking for special prayer for
my friend Kathy. She has been attending
SDA churches for years and today,
hallelujah, she is being baptized into
the SDA church. I would have put this in
the YouTube chat for prayer in Sabbath,
but but but she's in Eastern time. Um
and so so thank you all. so much. I love
you, church family. And we are going to
keep her in prayer. Thank you. Thank
you, brother Rain. Yes, she needs prayer
now like never before. Uh as we're going
to reach out to God and ask him to
protect her and and honoring that choice
of that decision that she just uh that
she's made. There was some uh pray
prayer requests from
Lena Regina. She says, "Priest, please
pray for Ilia Dia uh aka Mandukes and
her situation, asking God to move in her
favor and to show
the entire family his love and power."
Praise God. Um
she also want she said, "Please pray for
the unhoused. Pray for those that are
struggling financially. Please pray for
my niece uh Madison to get discharged
from the hospital. Please pray for mom's
physical healing and spiritual strength.
Uh amen. We're going to put all of
those. Thank you for that prayer
request. We will be praying over those
uh those requests. And there's also a
prayer request from sister from Vi I'm
I'm sorry VI Zion restore. It says um
please pray for me and my relationships
with my mother and father. Two different
circumstances.
But I haven't talked to my father in
over a year. My relationship with my
mother is strained. Pray for also pray
for the Jenkins family as a whole that
if it's not through me they come to the
understanding of Bible truths. Uh that
they come to the understanding of Bible
truths. Praise God. We're going to put
that in prayer. And we know that that is
God's desire for this family as well.
Esther Lita White, she says, "Please
pray. Please continue to pray
for me and my family. I am asking for
spiritual healing and physical healing.
And then the right, it's the right
stuff. That's what the right stuff for
you. 305. Please pray for my friend
Lynn's brother Lawrence. He was rushed
to the hospital praying for his
spiritual conviction of Jesus Christ and
his savior
as his savior and for his physical
health. peace for the family. Amen. So,
let's go to the throne of grace and
mercy. And I just want to invite all our
prayer warriors and everyone listening
in to just let our thoughts go up to
heaven as we're putting these petitions
before the throne room of grace and
mercy.
>> Loving Father, we're just so grateful.
And God, as we begin to pray, we
remember your promises. Lord, you said,
"Call on me and I will answer and show
you great and mighty things that you
know not of." Father, you also in your
word it says Lord that you sent forth
your word and you heal us of all of our
diseases. Father you al your word also
said that you delight in mercy and you
also says thank you Lord.
Father, you you invited us to come to
the throne room of grace and mercy to
come with confidence, Lord, and that the
prayer as we come, Lord, um that our
prayers would be heard and you would
answer. And we thank you, God, for your
many, many promises as we lift up every
petition, Father. every family, Lord.
And I mention the families that having
relationship issues. Father, we pray the
breach. Lord, we pray rebuild the broken
altars of family. Those relationships
are so important. Father, I'm praying
for the ministry of reconciliation to be
had. Jesus said, "I came to uh bind up
their wounds and to mend their broken
hearts." Father, men hearts. Help uh
help your children to be able to
forgive. Help them, God, to be able and
willing to reconcile, to put aside their
differences. Father, I just pray that
you just breathe your tender their
tenderness over them, God, and heal them
everywhere they're hurt. Father, help
them to be able to forgive. and God bind
up the wound because it's forgiving does
not mean that the hurt was not inflicted
but God it means that in spite of the
affliction that heaven goes through and
bind up the wound from that inflict that
that infliction and and heal Lord
everywhere they hurt Father I lift them
up before you in the name of Jesus
Father help I pray for families to be
able to come together men their broken
hearts God and God give them the
strength give them the strength to
forgive and to wrap their arms of love
around each other. God, I'm praying God
for the ministry of reconciliation be
between these families because Lord, it
was so important to you that you sent
your son to reconcile fallen man back to
yourself. And Lord, in that doing and
all that came to Christ, he also gave us
the ministry of reconciliation. So,
Father, I pray mend the brokenness in
these families. Rebuild these family
relationships. Reunite them in
closeness, Lord, and love in the name of
Jesus. Lord, I pray for those that are
needing spiritual healing. Oh God, send
forth your Holy Spirit. Send it, Lord,
down. Let it rain down on your children
in the name of Jesus. Oh God, that it
will renew them. It will rejuvenate
them. Oh God, I pray that you lead them
into your word. that that word is a
healing bomb that just flows over your
children from the top of their head to
the bottom of their feet. Help them God
to put a past any to to put us to set
aside any past hurts or hindrances that
they have experienced in their lives.
Show them God that man will fail them
but you never will. That Lord that you
would ask you Lord to take them by their
hand and lead them God. Leave them. Take
them up higher that they can feel your
presence. They can feel your fullness.
They can experience your joy. They can
experience your peace. And God, that
ever abiding love that you give. Oh
Lord, remind them of the great love that
you had for them when you gave your son
Jesus Christ. And not I had had, it's
not had, you still have. But Lord, in
the pouring out as a sin offering of
Christ, demonstrated to fallen man the
length, the width, the depth, the
height, the breath of the great love
that you have for them. And God, remind
your children of this that they will be
healed. Lord, we know that there is no
earthly sorrow that heaven cannot heal.
Oh God, let the son of righteousness
arise with healing in his wings and
restore God the the the the dull spirit
of your children. Restore them God.
Regenerate them Lord that the joy of the
Lord is their strength. I also pray for
physical healing. Sometime physical
healing can usurp the spiritual
breath from us. It can take us so down
sometimes. Father, heal them everywhere
they're hurt in the name of Jesus.
Father, I pray that you help them to to
do the things uh to live a lifestyle
that would be instrumental in in
promoting health in their bodies. And
God, help them to take hold of the arm
of omnipotence, Lord, until their change
come, having faith and trust in you
because you said, Lord, that you sent
forth your word and you health your land
of all of their diseases. You are the
great physician that bring about
healing, Lord. You can use whatever
modality of choice you select, but
ultimately all power comes from the
throne room of grace and mercy. And we
thank you for that. Lord, bring healing.
I pray for their healing mentally,
emotionally, physically, spiritually,
financially, even in their
relationships. Dear father, Lord, bless
your children. Restore your children in
the name of Jesus. hand. God, I pray God
that as you raise them up out of their
sick bed, because Lord, we know that you
are a doctor in a sick room. You are a
lawyer in a courtroom. Oh God, whatever
your children need, you are that. And we
know that man's extremities when we've
come to our extreme. It gives you an
opportunity, God, to show what nobody
else but God can do. So Lord, reveal
your power, reveal your love, reveal
your healing strength, God, and and on
behalf of your children. And Lord, I
want to pray for the sister that got
baptized today. Oh God, I pray that you
surround her with angels that excel in
power and strength because just as sure
she made a choice, was baptized. Oh God,
sometimes the gates of hell try to come
forth, but God, we ask you protect her.
Keep that decision, Lord, and honor that
choice that she has made. Help her to
stay committed. Help her to not get
discouraged. Surround her with a loving
family that's going to play not that's
going to pray not not just for her, but
that would pray with her. Father, we
lift her up before the blood stained
banner. Thanking you, God, for you alone
have done in her heart to bring her to
this decision, but God, keep that which
she has committed up unto you this day.
keeper of God against the the fiery
darts of the enemy because he's going to
throw them. But God, we stand on your
word that says no weapon formed against
her will prosper. Hallelujah. Praise
God, Father. And let her I pray that she
blossoms. I pray that she experience
abundant life in Christ Jesus, God. And
that the joy of the Lord is her
strength. keep her, keep her family,
Lord, and all that pertains to her for
the great commitment, Lord, that
decision that she made, Lord, to follow
Christ, to follow the lamb wheresoever
he goeth. I'm praying, oh God, for any
silent petitions or even, Lord, covering
those requests that I let them have an
opportunity to get in uh on the living
mana chat platform. Lord, cover your
people, strengthen your people. Lord,
you see every petition, you know the
heart of every person. You also know the
unspoken request. Oh God, rain down from
heaven and and reveal your strength.
Reveal your power. Reveal, oh God, that
there's nothing too hard for you. Lord,
lift up the hung down head. Father,
relieve them from depression and anxiety
in the name of Jesus. Father, move in
the lives of your people. Stretch forth
your mighty hand and interrupt anything
that the enemy is bringing against them
or bringing to them in the name of
Jesus. Block him. Stop him, Lord, and
just move him right on out of the way.
Lord, we're standing here in confidence,
not because of us, because we have
nothing. But Lord, our confidence is
only in our savior Jesus Christ, the
lamb of righteousness that was slain
before the foundation of this world.
Hallelujah. Who have loved us with an
everlasting love and is fighting on our
behalf. So, Father, wrap your arms
around your children, your little ones.
Let them feel your power. Let them feel
your warmth embrace. And God, let the
comforting, let that comforting bomb,
that healing bomb that flows only from
you. Let it just penetrate their entire
being. I pray this in the name of
Christ, your son, and our loving savior.
Amen and amen.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> Praise God.
>> Bless you. Thank you, Sister Jackie.
Amen.
>> Praise God.
>> Let us continue, Lord, to be at the
throne of grace, as we lift up your
people today, Lord, in Jesus name.
Father, we come in agreement, Lord,
because we know there's power in
agreement. Father, I'm already going to
say thank you for hearing and answering
the prayers in advance, Lord, because
you've given us that authority. You've
given us that power, Lord. We line up
our prayer and our faith, Lord, with
what heaven's voice has already given us
to kingdom authority, spiritual
authority, Lord, to speak these things,
Lord, and blessings over the people's
lives that you have put us in charge of.
So Lord, I thank you in advance, Lord,
in the mighty name of Jesus. Father,
>> oh God, thank you, Lord. Father, I want
to give praise to the baptism she
mentioned earlier, Lord.
>> My heart just reach joy when I hear
that, Lord. I know your angels are
singing and praising right now, Lord,
for that saved soul. So Lord, thank you.
>> Thank you, Jesus.
>> Thank you for that baptism in the name
of Jesus. Father, Father, I just want to
read these prayers to you now. Uh these
prayer, I lift them up to you, Lord.
Each and every one of them, Father.
Women of women of God for life. Lord,
please pray for my left knee, right hip,
still dealing with with lots of pain.
>> Father, I lift up Leela Peterson's
prayer request for for our family member
uh to know Jesus as well as the move and
the plan they have to move. Father, we
come by faith before you with that one.
And Father, I know this is my sister's
daughter. We pray for her, Lord. Uh
Nahheem, Lord, we pray for her blood
pressure.
>> Yes, God.
>> Uh still fluctuating, Lord. is still
having vertigo. Lord, we come to you in
the name of Jesus on this request, Lord.
>> And Sister Karen 9808,
>> yes.
>> Please pray for the renewing of the
mind.
>> Yes.
>> Unable to let go of the past. Oh God.
>> Oh God, we say we lift this up to you by
faith. And father, we pray for Seb
Grace. Uh please pray for the Kirk
family. Amen. We lift them up as well.
Yes. James 5382.
Please pray for the Tracy and her family
that they grow stronger in faith. Amen.
>> Yes, Lord.
>> And MT prayer for JB that God will break
chains of mental confusion. Amen.
>> Mighty clarity come quickly, Lord. Amen.
Father, in the name of Jesus, Lord.
>> Father, I'm just stuck on this quote
that I heard last week, Lord. And I come
to the throne of grace with this in my
mind where it says, man, we want to lift
this up by faith. Lord,
>> heaven's voice over the world's noise.
Lord, there's so much of that going on
right now. So, Father, as we come to the
throne of throne of grace, Father, we
know that you hear our petitions. Yes.
>> And as we lift them up to you, Lord, we
do it by faith.
>> Lord, hear your prayers tonight. Honor
your people's faith, Lord, in the name
of Jesus. Lord, by faith, Lord, we lift
them up to you in the name of Jesus.
Lord, quiet the noise. Lord, assure your
people that you have them in the palm of
your hands in the mighty name of Jesus.
Walk with them, talk with them, Lord.
Let them hear you, Lord. Magnify your
voice, Lord, and let them see where
you're working in their lives, Lord,
because you are and you've given us that
authority, Lord. I decree declare and
decree Lord this faith and by by the
sound of my voice Lord I pray your
blessings over each and every petition
right now. You've given us that
authority Lord kingdom's authority Lord
not my f not my strength but yours Lord
the power Lord. Thank you Jesus.
>> Thank you Lord for allowing us Lord to
be part of that rock. We're not the rock
but you have put a hidden vessel in us
Lord that we can speak these things
>> with power and conviction Lord. So
seeking blessings over the people,
things that have already been said and
done. We're fighting from a place of
>> of victory. Amen. Hallelujah. Of
victory. It's already been said and
done. So we declare it in the name of
Jesus. Father, thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you for that thing. Thank you for
that blessing. Thank you for that power.
Thank you for that authority, Lord. So
we put it on. We stand on the promises
of God, Lord. standing in the gap for
your people, Lord, to hear their cry,
Lord, in the name of Jesus. Lord, thank
you, Lord. And Lord, we pray for the
prayers of healing right now, Lord.
Every request, Lord, everywhere they
hurt, Lord Jesus, touch them, Lord.
Asking for your divine healing, Lord. I
take this one touch, Lord. You're the
major physician, Lord. Lord, put a put a
blessing upon them, Lord, that and let
them know, Lord, it it was you, Father,
that brought them through in the name of
Jesus. Lord, thank you, Lord. Every
healing prayer, Lord, that has gone up
to you right now, Lord. Right hip, left
knee,
>> all of these things, Lord, aching, pain,
vertigo. Father, we lift it all up to
you right now, Lord.
>> Bring them down and give them peace,
Lord God, in the name of Jesus. We know
how this painful it can be to sit around
aching in pain. So, Father, I pray that
you pour out a blessing over them right
now. A healing blessed name.
>> Give them double portions Lord of peace,
joy, and calmness, Lord. All these
things, Lord, that only you can do,
Lord. And do we do thank we lift up
their positions, Lord. But, Father,
we're asking you to be the major
>> Yes.
>> major positions in their life. Draw them
closer to you spiritually, Lord. Yes.
>> In the name of Jesus, Lord, we praise
you and we thank you, Lord.
>> Thank you, Lord. And all this mental
noise, Lord,
>> that we speak of, Lord. We know the
devil's busy in that, Lord. So, we come
against it. We speak the word of God
over it right now.
>> Yes, Lord.
>> Bring every thought captive, Lord. We
speak the word of God over each and
every Lord. Renew their minds, Lord.
Renew their strength, Lord. Let them be
transformed, Lord. And, Father, let them
know who we're doing. Assure them, Lord,
that it is you, Father. Keep their eyes
upon you in the name of Jesus. I pray,
Lord. And Father, as we transition into
our our uh our our main service today,
Lord, we ask that you be with our pastor
today.
>> Yes, Father.
>> Father, thank you, Lord. Lord, he is
laboring for you like no other, Lord.
You have given them word for your
people, Lord. Feed your sheep, Lord,
with the word of God today, Lord. And I
know he waits patiently, Lord, to share
it and serve his people, Lord, in the
name of Jesus. So, thank you for pastor,
Lord. Cover him and anoint him, Lord.
lead and guide him and strengthen him,
Lord, in the name of Jesus. Lord, bless
his day. Bless him and his wife, their
union, and all that they stand in need
of. Yes. In the name of Jesus. Thank
you, Lord, for hearing and answering our
prayer today in Jesus name. Amen.
>> Amen. And amen. Praise God.
>> Thank you, saints.
>> Thank you.
When did I start to forget
all of the great things you did.
When did I throw away faith for the
impossible?
How did I start to believe
you weren't sufficient for me?
Why do I talk myself out of seeing
miracles?
You are more than able.
Who am I to deny what the Lord can do?
It's easy for you.
And now I see all that I have.
And I've got my confidence back.
I put my trust in the one who still does
mirales.
You do mirales.
You are more than able.
>> You are more than able.
Yes,
you are more than able.
Yes, you are Lord. Yes,
Who am I to deny what the Lord can do?
Can you imagine
with all of the faith in the room what
the Lord can do? What the Lord can do.
And it's going to happen.
Just let the way make it through. He's
going to move.
He's going to move.
Can you imagine
with all of the faith in the room what
the Lord can do? what the Lord can do.
And it's going to happen
just like the way you make it through.
He's going to move.
Anything is possible.
Who am I to deny what the Lord can do?
Anything is possible for you.
Anything is possible.
Who am I to deny what the Lord can do?
You are more than able.
Yes, you are God.
I believe
you are more than able.
Who am I to deny what the Lord can't do?
Come a long way.
I've seen how you work.
There's so much goodness in praise.
much more than I deserve.
And I know why I am.
And I can't stay where I'm at.
We've come this far by faith
and I just can't turn back.
So come on my soul
shy on me
cuz you've got a lion inside of those
lones. Get up and praise the Lord.
>> You're not.
>> So come on my soul.
Don't you get shy on me. Lift up your
song. You've got a lion inside of those.
Get up and embrace the Lord.
So come on my show. Well, don't you get
shy on me. Lift up your song.
You got a lion inside of those lungs.
Get up and praise the Lord.
>> Come on, my soul.
Don't you get shy on me. Lift up your
song cuz you got a lion inside of those
lungs and get up and praise the Lord.
So I throw up my head and praise you
again and again.
>> Cuz all that I have is
nothing else for a king.
for heart single
hallelujah.
You are more than able.
Hallelujah.
Who am I to deny what the Lord can't do?
Who am I to deny what the Lord can do?
You are more
than able.
Heat.
Well done, good and faithful servant.
Welcome home.
Heat. Heat.
Heat up
here.
Heat. Heat.
Amen. Good evening. Good afternoon
everyone. Um
we are getting ready to get into the
word of God today. Um I want to
encourage you
if you have not already shared this link
to please go ahead and do so. Now we are
about
uh to go on a journey into the word of
God. Thank you graphic team.
Uh I think that was a excellent setup
for the message today. And today we're
going to be talking about two subjects
uh that have
captured the attention of the Christian
world. We're going to be talking about
the Sabbath and hellfire.
Um, so please let's take a moment to
pray and then we're going to jump into
this message, this topic that many
people uh have been addressing
um particularly over the last several
weeks. Let's go ahead and pray. Again,
hit that share button. Invite, invite,
invite. you're not want to want to m
miss this. Um so please let people know
that uh this is this message is
beginning. Let's pray. Heavenly Father
uh speak to us, Lord.
Lord, I pray that you would make this
subject crystal clear. And Lord, as we
hear things that we may have never heard
before today, I pray that the spirit of
conviction will settle into our hearts.
So Lord speak now as our prayer in Jesus
name. Amen. And amen.
Beloved, um
after um
Charlie Kirk's assassination,
uh there was a lot of talk about a book
that he had just written uh on the
Sabbath.
And that book was released uh a few days
ago.
And uh in the book he addresses the
question of the Sabbath.
and uh his position
was that the Sabbath was still useful
for the Christian.
Um
that
uh the Sabbath uh was on the seventh day
of the week, but if you could not
observe it, um you could choose another
day. So really the emphasis of the book
was about honoring a Sabbath. Honoring a
Sabbath.
And there have been a lot of people
talking about that position. Is that is
that a biblical position? Um is it not?
Is the Sabbath still to be kept? Is it
only for the Jews? What what what is a
Sabbath really about?
On top of that, just a few weeks ago,
um,
uh, another very well-known,
Christian apologist, Kirk Cameron,
came out with
a new belief.
Want to make sure you guys could hear
me. came out with a with a change of
belief. Let me say that
he now believed that hellfire
uh as is popularly believed by many
Christians is not in the Bible. That the
idea of an eternally burning hell is not
scriptural. And so these two subjects,
which are heavy subjects in and of
themselves,
um
would would typically be tackled
individually
because they're two major subjects.
But today, we're going to be looking at
both of these
subjects
in one.
and we're going to find out what the
Bible actually says about these two
things.
Um, we're going to find out is the
Sabbath is it according to our choice.
You know, we may say, hey, you know, I
prefer the seventh day of the week, but
if I can't do the seventh day, then, you
know, maybe I could just choose another
day as long as I'm choosing a day. And
the question of an eternally burning
hell is hell something that burns
forever or
do many Christians have it wrong?
And so we are going to take a look at
the word of God today. And what we're
going to do you guys again is we're
going to go through a very methodical
study of the word. And you're going to
see some things that are absolutely
amazing.
So let's begin. We're going to go to our
first slide.
And
what I want you to note here, the first
thing I'm going to I'm going to I'm
going to mention I'm going to say is
this that many Christians believe that
the fires of God,
hellfire is eternal. It is eternal.
The fire that burns is eternal. And I'm
going to say that that is absolutely
true. That is absolutely true. Notice
with me Matthew chapter 25 and verse 41.
Jesus speaking here says, "Then shall he
say unto them also on the left hand,
depart from me, ye cursed
into everlast into everlasting fire
prepared for the devil and his angels."
We clearly see here that the fire is
everlasting.
The fire is everlasting. Notice again
with me verse 46 of the same chapter.
Um
then shall he say unto them, actually we
just we just read this and actually
yep, we got two separate verses here,
but it's okay. Um, what we're seeing
here
once again is that the fire is
everlasting.
In Mark chapter 9:43,
the Bible says, "And if thy hand offend
thee, cut it off. It is better for thee
to enter into life maimed than having
two hands to go into hell into the fire
that shall never be quenched."
the fire that shall never be quenched.
So again, we see here clearly that the
fire is eternal. One more, Jude 1:7,
even as Sodom and Gomorrah and the
cities about them in like manner, giving
themselves over to fornication and going
after strange flesh are set forth for an
example, suffering the vengeance of
eternal fire. So here's what I want to
to to um for you to understand
first and foremost
that the word here eternal
means
that the fire is everlasting
and most Christians would agree with
that the fire is everlasting. Now the
fact that the word eternal is used that
the word that the words forever is used
when it comes to the fire
we must be willing to apply this
principle
um consistently.
Let's go back to the screen and I want
you to notice something.
In Exodus chapter 31 16 and 17, the
Bible says, "Wherefore the children of
Israel shall keep the Sabbath to observe
the Sabbath throughout their generations
for a perpetual covenant. It is a sign
between me and the children of Israel
forever.
For in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, and on the seventh day he rested
and was refreshed. Now, please
understand that if we're going to say
that hellfire is definitely eternal
because words like forever and
everlasting and and and and uh um
eternity or eternal are applied to
hellfire,
we must also equally apply it when it is
used regarding the Sabbath.
The Sabbath is a perpetual covenant. It
is a sign between between the children
of Israel forever.
Excellent. Excellent. Are we good so
far?
Now the question is asked but for whom?
But for whom? Let's go ahead and see in
the commandment itself
in Exodus 20:10. The Bible says but the
seventh day is the Sabbath of the Lord
thy God. In it, thou. And the thou there
is referring to the Jew, the Jewish
person, the Israelite. In it, thou shalt
not do any work. Thou shalt not do any
work. Meaning you are to keep the
Sabbath. Israelite, you shall not do any
work. That's how you keep the Sabbath.
By not doing any work. This commandment
extends to the Israelites son forever.
to the Israelites daughter
forever. And now notice this, it also
extends to the Israelites manservant,
maid servant, even the animals. And now
watch this, the stranger
that is within thy gates. Now what would
the stranger within thy gate mean? Who
would be the stranger
within the gates of an Israelite?
It would re it would be a gentile.
Let me show you a little bit more about
these gates. When the Bible says gates,
notice with me in Jeremiah 17:21, thus
sayith the Lord, take heed to yourselves
and bear no burden on the Sabbath day,
nor bring it in by the gates
of Jerusalem.
Again, Nehemiah 13:1 19. And it came to
pass that when the gates of Jerusalem
began to be darkened before the Sabbath,
I commanded that the gates be not shut
be shut and charged that they should not
be opened until after the Sabbath and
some of my servants I set at the gates
that no burden should be brought in it
on the Sabbath day. So the gates here is
not a reference to to an Israelites
personal house. Yes, it could be read
that way. But this command was for
anyone living in Israel, Jew or Gentile.
Put a one in the chat if that makes
sense, please.
So then what we see so far is this
eternal hell or or eternal fire
is eternal because the word eternal is
used. We don't need to question, hey, is
it eternal or is it not eternal? The
fire is eternal.
But according to the same logic, the
Sabbath is also eternal.
The word perpetual and forever is
applied to the Sabbath. Now remember the
Sabbath commandment. Yes, it was given
to the Jew, but it was also given to the
Gentile.
The stranger that would have been in the
gates of Jerusalem was also to honor the
Sabbath
forever.
I want you to note with me Numbers
15:13. The Bible says, "All that are
born of the country shall do these
things after the manner in an offering
offering in an offering made by fire of
a sweet savor unto the Lord. An
ordinance shall be for you be both for
you of the congregation and also for the
stranger
that sjouneth with you, an ordinance
forever in your generations. as as ye
also. So, so the stranger shall be
before the Lord.
One law for the stranger
and
for the Jew.
Now
you say, "But pastor, again, that was
the Old Testament." Let me read to you
from Isaiah 56:es 4 and 5, a chapter
that is referring to the Gentiles coming
into the blessings that were originally
for the Jews.
The Bible says, "For thus sayith the
Lord unto the Unix that keep my Sabbaths
and choose the things that please me and
take hold of my covenant. Even unto them
will I give in my house and within my
walls a palace and a name better than of
sons and of daughters. And I will give
them an everlasting name that shall not
be cut off. Also the sons of the
strangers. Now who would the sons of the
strangers be?
The sons of the strangers would be
Gentiles.
The text says, "Also the sons of the
strangers that join themselves to the
Lord to serve him,
and to love the name of the Lord, to be
his servants, everyone that keepeth the
Sabbath from polluting it, and taketh
hold of my covenant." Watch. Even them
will I bring to my holy mountain, and
make their make them joyful in my house
of prayer. Their burnt offerings and
their sacrifices shall be acceptable
upon mine offer. For mine house shall be
called a house of prayer for how many
people?
How many people? For the Jews?
No, not for the Jews, but for all
people. Therefore, in Isaiah chapter 56,
we have here a direct prophecy stating
that the Sabbath would also extend to
the Gentiles.
Thus, the Sabbath would also be forever
as the text states.
Now, here is a question.
We're going to go back to hellfire for a
moment. Why is the fire eternal?
Why is the fire eternal? Let me tell you
why. Because, beloved, listen carefully.
The fire is eternal. Because the fire
is strongly connected with God himself.
In other words, the fire is a revelation
of the character of God. Please note
with me on the screen Hebrews 12 verse
29. The Bible says here, "For our God is
a consuming
fire."
Now, if our God is a consuming fire, it
would make sense then that the fire that
destroys the wicked must be eternal.
Why? Because it is
an
it is an outgrowth. It is the result of
the very presence of God. Come on, let
me show you again. Malachi 3:2. But who
may abide the day of his coming? And who
shall stand when he appearth? For he is
like a refiner's fire and like fuller
soap. He shall sit as a refiner and
purifier of silver and shall purify the
sons of Levi and purge them as gold and
silver that they may offer unto the Lord
an offering in righteousness. The fire
of God is eternal.
Listen carefully to me. Not because the
wicked are eternal, but because God is
eternal.
The fire is a manifestation of God. Now,
I want you to note with me the book Song
of Solomon's chapter 8:6. What is fire
symbolic of in the Bible? The Bible says
this, "Set me as a seal upon thine
heart, as a seal upon thine arm. For
love is strong as death. Jealousy is
cruel as the grave. The coals thereof
are coals of fire, which have a most
vehement flame. Many waters cannot
quench love,
neither can the floods drown it. In
other words, beloved, what the Bible is
telling us here is that God
manifests himself as fire because fire
is a symbol of love.
The Bible tells us in 1 John chapter
4:8, "He that loveth not knoweth not
God, for God is fire."
God is fire.
God is love. The very presence of God is
fire.
That is why the fire is eternal because
God is eternal.
All right. Now watch this. Remember when
God made Adam and Eve, Adam and Eve were
not afraid of God or his presence. They
could stand in his presence without
being consumed. However, when they
sinned, the Bible tells us that they
were no longer equipped to stand in the
presence of God. Meaning, they were now
afraid of the fire. Notice with me,
Genesis 3:8. And they heard the voice of
the Lord God walking in the garden in
the cool of the day. And Adam and his
wife hid themselves from the presence of
the Lord God amongst the trees of the
garden. I want you to understand,
beloved, that what they were hiding from
was the consuming fire. You see,
beloved, to those who follow God, God is
a refining fire. But to those who reject
God, God is a consuming fire. The fire
is eternal not because the wicked are
eternal but because God is eternal and
the fire is a manifestation of his
character which is love. This is why
this is why the Bible tells us in Exodus
3:2 that when Moses is in the wilderness
and he meets God for the first time, the
Bible says the angel of the Lord
appeared unto him in a flame of fire out
of the midst of the bush and he looked
and behold the bush burned with fire and
the bush was not consumed. Here is what
I need you to understand, beloved, that
God's desire for you and I is to be able
to stand in his fiery presence like that
burning bush and not be consumed.
So you'll remember
as an example, you'll remember that when
Shadrach, Meshach, and Abednego were
cast into a burning fiery furnace that
the the fire burned but did not consume
them. It did not consume them. The Bible
says in Daniel 3:2, Nebuchadnezzar
speaking after he has thrown them into
the fire, he answered and said, "Lo, I
see four men loose walking in the midst
of the fire, and they have no hurt, and
the form of the fourth is like the Son
of God."
The Bible goes on to say, "Then
Nebuchadnezzar came near to the mouth of
the burning fiery furnace. He couldn't
go in it. He could only come near it."
Remember the men that threw them in were
destroyed by that fire. But because God
was a refining fire to Shadrach, Meach,
and Abednego, are y'all listening to me?
The fire had no pe no effect upon them.
He said, "Shadrach, Meshach, and
Abednego, you servants of the most high
God, come forth and come hither." Then
Shadrach, Meshach, and Abednego came
forth out of the midst of the fire.
Watch this. And the princes, governors,
and captains, and the king's counselors
being gathered together saw these men
upon whose bodies the fire had no power,
nor was a hair of their head singed,
neither was their were their coats
changed, nor the smell of fire had
passed upon them. I'm going to ask you
this. Y'all put a five in the chat if
you would like to have the experience of
Shadrach, Meshach, and Abednego where
the fire has no power over you. Put a
five in the chat for me, please.
We are breaking this down methodically.
I pray that someone sends this message
to Kirk Cameron. Why? Because Kirk
Cameron is getting beat up right now for
he has abandoned the faith.
He now believes that hellfire is not
eternal.
Do you know how many people do not
understand this concept that the reason
that the fire is eternal is not because
the wicked are eternal but it is because
God is eternal. That's why the fire is
eternal. We're going to deal with what
happens in the wicked in that fire
momentarily. But for now, for now, we
have seen
that the reason the fire is eternal is
because God is eternal. Okay. What about
the Sabbath?
Why is the Sabbath
eternal?
eternal? By the way, we are told in
Isaiah 66, and I will read it a little
bit later. In Isaiah 66, the Bible
literally says, "For as the new heavens
and the new earth which remain before
me, sayeth the Lord, shall remain, so
shall your name remain. And it shall
come to pass that from one Sabbath to
another, and one new moon to another
will all flesh come before me and
worship." We see in Isaiah 66
a very clear reference that the Sabbath
will be honored in the new Jerusalem
which means it is eternal.
So
if hellfire or if the fire that destroys
hell
isn't that something else? Didn't didn't
Kirk Cameron have a movie called
Fireproof? Little did he know,
little did he know
that that concept of being fireproof.
Lord have mercy.
May millions of others wake up like he
did to this truth.
So then, so then if if hellfire is
eternal
only because that fire is actually the
fire of God
and because God is eternal, it is
eternal. What about the Sabbath?
What about the Sabbath?
Well, let's find out. Let's go back to
Genesis chapter 2. Genesis chapter 2:es
2 and 3. And the Bible says here, the
Bible says here, um, and on the seventh
day God rested
from all the work
or he ended his work which he had made.
And he rested on the seventh day from
all his work which he had made.
And God blessed the seventh day and
sanctified it because that in it he had
rested from all his work which God
created and made. I I want y'all to
understand something about this
commandment
about this this Sabbath.
The Sabbath came about not a a not as a
result of God
doing something.
The Sabbath came from God not doing
something, but the Sabbath came from God
not doing something.
Let me say that again.
The Sabbath came from God not doing
something, but it came from God not
doing something.
In other words,
God simply ceased
to do something and that is what
produced the Sabbath. That is what that
is how the Sabbath became a thing. It is
not because God did something. It is
that God ceased. Now I want you to
understand this. I want you to
understand how does something become
holy? Because in that moment, God
stopped everything.
I want you to understand how hard of a
thing this is to fathom that the God of
the universe
who does and creates and and and
is always working
somehow
in a way that we can't understand
ceased
for 24 hours.
and and the mere fact that he ceased
from doing in that 24-hour period made
the day holy.
God sanctified that period
because he ceased
doing work. I don't I don't know if we
can. It might be something hard to grasp
and understand. But beloved, here's what
you need to see. That time period is
mysterious and holy.
Not because God did something, but
because God did not do in that 24-hour
period.
Let all the earth be silent. Be still.
On this day, God was still.
On this day, God rested. On this day,
God ceased.
Everything stopped.
Now, you need to understand this.
God explains in his own word. He says,
"Moreover also, I gave them my Sabbath
to be a sign between me and them, that
they might know that I am the Lord that
sanctify them."
You know what? Let me go back to this
for a moment. Do y'all remember the
game? Was it Is it musical chairs? Like
when the music stops, you have to sit
down. There might be another game I'm
thinking of, but I can't remember it.
where where the leader whatever he's
doing when he stops you have to stop.
It's almost like a a reverence for the
leader in that game. And I don't
remember the name of the game. I wish I
did. Maybe you you'll remember it in the
chat. But when you when the leader
stops, you have to stop. Think about
that for a second. the God of the
universe stops
and in the mere stopping it becomes a
holy thing. It's almost like in the mere
stopping there is something that is
being said about the character
of God.
The Sabbath then when he sanctified it,
the Sabbath in essence becomes the
symbol that God is a sanctifier,
the sanctifier, the only one that can
sanctify anything. The Sabbath becomes
the symbol that God's character is one
that sanctifies. Therefore, beloved,
listen to me. The Sabbath then itself is
an outgrowth of the very character of
God who is the sanctifier. Therefore, we
can understand that just as hellfire is
eternal because the fire is connected to
God and God is eternal. So the fact that
as long as God is the sanctifier,
the Sabbath must also be eternal as it
is connected to the character of God.
Why can't the fire ever go out? Because
God is eternal.
Why can't the Sabbath ever cease to be?
Because God is eternal. And the Sabbath
and fire are both manifestations of the
character of God.
Watch this. You guys watch this. In
Deuteronomy, in Hebrews chapter 2:1, the
Bible says, "For both he that
sanctifieth
and they who are sanctified are all of
one, for which cause he's not ashamed to
call them brethren." So beloved, the
Sabbath is the is the acknowledgment and
the remembering that God is the
sanctifier.
And one who sanctifies, the very first
thing sanctified in the Bible is the
Sabbath. And God does that for the
planet, not for the Jews, for the
planet.
Let all the earth be silent.
When God ceases, be still. When God is
still, be still.
God set that thing in action. And I need
to show you something because the
Sabbath, beloved, is in essence a sign
not only of God's character, but of
God's mercy. Let me show you. In
Deuteronomy 5:14, the Bible says, "But
on the seventh day is a Sabbath of the
Lord thy God. In it thou shalt not do
any work, thou nor thy son, nor thy
daughter, nor thy man's servant, nor thy
maid servant, nor thine ox, nor thine
ass, nor thy cattle, nor thy stranger
that is within thy gates. For uh that
thy man's servant, and thy maidervant
may rest as well as thou. Everybody, I
want everybody to rest. Hey, I rested so
that you could rest. Now, you rest so
that others could rest. Do you see how
that works? Watch this, yo.
God rested
so that his people could rest.
And then he says, "Turn around and and I
want you to rest so that those who serve
you will also have rest. The stranger
that is within your gate will have
rest." In other words, beloved, God set
the example for us to follow. And then
he says, "I want you to extend that
Sabbath rest to others.
Watch this. Watch this. And remember
that you were a servant in the land of
Egypt, and that the Lord your God
brought you out then through a mighty
hand, and by stretched out arm.
Therefore, the Lord commanded you to
keep the Sabbath day. God says, listen,
the Sabbath is a reminder
of the character
of the individual that set us free.
Therefore, as long as that individual
exists,
the symbol that he uses to say remind
yourself of who freed you exists.
To get rid of the Sabbath, you have to
get rid of God.
For the fire to go out, you have to get
rid of God.
Neither can be done because God is
everlasting.
The Bible says in Isaiah 58:13 and 14,
"If you turn away your foot from the
Sabbath from doing your pleasure on my
holy day, call the Sabbath a delight and
holy and honorable and shall honor him,
not doing your own ways, nor finding
your own pleasure, then shall you
delight yourself in the Lord." Isaiah
58:6, I will read it in your hearing. It
says, "Is not the fast? Is not this the
fast that I have chosen to loose the
bands of wickedness, to undo the heavy
burdens, and to let the oppressed go
free, and that you break every yoke? Is
it not to deal thy bread to the hungry,
and that thou bring the poor that are
cast out into thy house when you see the
naked, that you cover him, and that you
hide not yourself from your own flesh?
In other words, beloved, the Sabbath is
the sign
that God is merciful
even to the strangers that are not like
us.
Did y'all hear that just now?
The Sabbath is the sign that God
loves
loves the immigrant
the person from another nation not like
ours.
In other words, beloved, if the world
actually kept the Sabbath, there would
be no such thing as racism,
as slavery,
as pride of national, we are better than
you.
The spirit behind the Sabbath is a
revelation of God's character. And
that's why the devil doesn't want people
really understanding the character of
God because when they understand the
character of God and that the Sabbath in
particular is a revelation of who this
God is and when we understand the
Sabbath is hey remember you were a slave
don't treat others like slaves remember
you were outcasts don't treat others
like outcasts remember you were
downtrodden don't don't downtrod others
don't speak ill about others don't speak
ill about people who are not born where
you are or who are not the same color
you are. Listen, this is a revelation of
the character of God. And in order for
the Sabbath to be done away with, you
have to do away with God because God's
character does not change.
The Sabbath is a sign of God's mercy
extended to others. And this is why
Psalms 118 verse1 says, "Oh, give thanks
unto the Lord for he is good because his
mercy, come on y'all,
his mercy endureth forever."
One of the signs of his mercy, beloved,
is the Sabbath where he says, "Let those
who are in your house or or in your
gates rest. Remember, you were a slave,
extend mercy.
Extend rest."
The Bible tells us in Psalm 90:2,
"Before the mountains were born, or ever
you had formed the earth or the world,
from everlasting to everlasting, you are
God." Here's what this means, beloved.
If God is God from everlasting to
everlasting, then that means the fire
has to be eternal. That means the
Sabbath has to be eternal because they
are both reflections of the very
character of God.
Here it is. Here it is. Isaiah 66 verse
22 and 23. And now I'm going to need
y'all to hold on to your seats. Hold on.
Hold on. I promise you. Hold on. Listen
to me, y'all. Isaiah 66:22 and 23 says
this. For as the new heavens and the new
earth which I will make shall remain
before me, say the Lord, so shall your
seed and your name remain. And it shall
come to pass that from one new moon to
another,
and from one Sabbath to another shall
all flesh come before me to worship. The
Sabbath is eternal. You just read it
right there. How is the Sabbath going to
be applicable in the Old Testament and
then done away in with in the New
Testament and then kept again in the new
heavens and earth? What kind of sense
does that make?
So the Sabbath is eternal, and those who
honor the Sabbath
will get to experience the Sabbath
eternally.
Okay,
guess what the next verse in this same
chapter says? If I say the next verse,
that would mean verse 24. So, we've just
read 22 and 23, which states that the
Sabbath is eternal. It's talking about
the Sabbath of God.
Let's see what the next verse says.
All right. Now, I'm going show you just
so that you see I didn't pull a trick
just now. Let's go back. There is verse
23,
the Sabbath. And here is verse 24.
And they shall go forth and look upon
the carcasses
of the men that have transgressed
against me. For their worm shall not
die. Neither shall their fire be
quenched,
and they shall be an aboring to all
flesh. Wow.
Why is Isaiah putting both Sabbath
and eternal fire in the same breath?
In one verse, in one set of verses.
Isaiah 66 22 23 24. You have the Sabbath
which is eternal and you have the fire
which shall not be quenched. Oh wow.
Oh wow.
If you are going to say that the fire of
hell is eternal, which most Christians
say, then you cannot in the very same
set of texts say the Sabbath is not
eternal. You can't do it. Either one is
eternal and one is not or both are
eternal or none are eternal.
Why is God himself
through the spirit? I told you. I told
you.
I told you. Why is God through the
spirit mentioning both an eternal
Sabbath and right next to it, eternal
fire?
If one is eternal, then both are
eternal.
And beloved, the fire is eternal, no
doubt. The Sabbath is also eternal, no
doubt. It's almost as if God is trying
to say, listen,
those who rest in me
will be able to stand in my eternal fire
and not be consumed.
Those
who honor my rest
on the earth
will be graced
because I sanctified them. They will
they will have eternal life and will be
able to stand in my presence without
being consumed.
Fireproof.
Two different sides, you guys, of the
same coin. The Sabbath and fire,
pastor. But the text says, "The worm
dies not." I want you to notice again
carefully, beloved, in Isaiah 66:4, they
shall go forth and look upon the
carcasses of the men. They are dead.
They are not alive in the fire. They are
dead.
They're not living. They're not
breathing.
The fire will destroy the wicked, but it
will leave them dead.
The end result of the eternal fire is
that it will leave the men who were
unprepared to stand in it dead.
Their carcasses.
Well, pastor, what about the worm that
shall not die? It's the worm that shall
not die, not the people. They are dead.
carcasses.
Notice the purpose of the worms for in
Isaiah 51:8. For the moth shall eat them
up like a guard, like a garment, and the
worm shall eat them like wool. What is
the worm eating? It's eating the body.
It is symbolic of total consummation of
the wicked to the wicked will be totally
consumed. Nothing left.
Unless you want to tell me that the
bodies of the wicked are eternal and
last forever and therefore the worm will
just be eating from them forever. That's
not what the Bible is saying. Beloved,
watch this. I I need y'all to watch and
follow this because the same thing is
stated in Revelation 14:10.
The Bible says, "The same shall drink of
the wine of the wrath of God, which is
poured out without mixture into the cup
of his indignation, and he shall be
tormented with fire and brimstone in the
presence of the holy angels and in the
presence of the lamb." Let me pause for
a second.
Do you realize what this text is saying?
It is saying that the wicked
will be tormented in the fire
in the presence of the lamb.
Where will the lamb be for all eternity?
The lamb will be in heaven for all
eternity.
So if the lamb is in heaven for all
eternity and the wicked are burning for
all eternity in the presence of the
lamb, meaning in the fire of the lamb,
then what that would mean is that the
wicked would be in heaven being
tormented forever. And we know that
that's not the case, beloved.
In other words, when Revelation 14:10
tells us that the wicked are tormented
in with fire and brimstone in the
presence of the holy angels and in the
presence of the lamb, it is telling us
that they are burning in the presence of
God until they are ultimately wiped out
and destroyed. And we will see that they
come to an end.
Watch this
next verse says this. And this throws
people. When you're not studying and
you're reading, taking for granted.
All right, everyone.
So, my slides have just frozen.
I don't know if my team can just forward
these slides for me, but uh yeah, my
slides are just stopped.
So, if there's a way that my team can
control this, if you could just go to
the next slide, that would be great. I'm
I'm just going to go ahead and read.
Revelation 14:11 says, "The smoke of
their torment ascendeth up forever and
ever, and they have no rest day nor
night, who worship the beast and his
image. And whosoever receiveth the mark
of his name, there it is on the screen.
I'm going to pause for a second. I want
you to notice first of all how
they are not being tormented.
It is the smoke of their torment that
ascends up forever and ever.
That means the remainder, the only thing
left of them is the smoke of their
torment.
When the text says they have no rest in,
isn't it interesting how it puts they
have no rest day nor night and beloved
it simply means that there is no break
there is no in there is no intermission
in their suffering. They suffer the full
sentence until they are fully destroyed.
This is what the text is saying. And I
will prove it to you as we go further
into the Bible.
They have no rest. Isn't it interesting?
Those who rejected the rest of God will
have no rest day nor night. They will
suffer until they become ashes. And then
notice how the text ends. Here is the
patience of the saints. Here are they
that keep the commandments of God and
have the faith of Jesus. Isn't it
interesting how not only in Isaiah 22 do
we see
do we see that the Sabbath and hellfire
are put together but in Revelation
chapter 14 we see keeping the
commandments of God and hellfire. Again,
the two things are brought together in
one
verse,
one group of verses.
Malachi chapter 4. Let me prove it to
you now, pastor. But the text says, let
me show you what Malachi chapter 4 says.
For behold, the day cometh that shall
burn as an oven, and all the proud, yay,
all that do wickedly shall be stubble,
and the day that cometh shall burn them
up, sayeth the Lord of hosts, that it
shall leave them neither root nor
branch.
The very next verse, verse three, goes
on to to say, "They shall be the wicked
shall be ashes under the souls of your
feet in the day that I shall do this.
The book of Psalms says the wicked will
vanish away into smoke.
So then, so then it now makes sense why
in the book of Hebrews chapter 4:9, the
Bible says, "There remainth therefore a
rest to the people of God." There
remainth a Sabbath, a sabotismos
to the people of God. Those who keep the
Sabbath now will ultimately enter into
the the heavenly Sabbath rest of God.
The Sabbathismos.
Look at what Isaiah 48:18 says. Oh, that
thou has hearken that that thou hast
hearkened to my commandments. Then had
thy peace been as a river, and thy
righteousness as the waves of the sea.
Watch. There is no peace,
say the Lord, unto the wicked.
Did you catch that?
There is no peace unto the wicked. The
wicked have no rest.
And because they have no rest,
because
because No, let me just show you. Let me
just show you. Come on, let's go back to
the screen. Psalm 37:10, "For yet a
little while, and the wicked shall cease
to be.
Yay, thou shalt diligently look for his
place, and it shall not be." God is
telling us that the end result of the
wicked who enter into the fire of God,
what the Bible calls hellfire,
will eventually
cease to exist.
When you say hell fire, when you say a
house fire, it means the fire burnt down
the house so that there's nothing left
of the house. When you say a church
fire, that means the fire burnt down the
church so that there is nothing left.
Beloved, when the Bible talks about
hellfire, what it's telling us is that
death and hell will be cast into fire,
the presence of God, and will be totally
consumed, so that there is nothing left.
Ezekiel 8:13, but it shall not be well
with the wicked, neither shall he
prolong his days, which are as a shadow,
because he fearth before God. The wicked
will not have prolonged days. The wicked
will be will cease to exist. And this is
this is exactly what the fire does. The
fire is eternal, not the wicked. How do
we know this? Because John 3:16 tells
us, "For God so loved the world that he
gave his only begotten son that
whosoever believeth in him should not
perish but have eternal life." The
wicked do not have eternal life.
The text does not say eternal uh life in
misery for the wicked. It says only the
righteous have eternal life.
The wicked do not have eternal life.
Therefore, they cannot live forever.
The Bible clearly tells us in Romans
6:23, "The wages of sin is death, but
the gift of God is eternal life." The
gift of God is not eternal life in
misery. The wages of sin is not eternal
life in misery. Eternal life is only
given to the righteous. And the opposite
of eternal life is to perish, to not
have life. It is not to have life at a
lower level of existence. It is not to
have eternal life in misery. That is not
the wages of sin. The wages of sin is
death where you cease to exist.
The fire is eternal. The wicked are not.
Let me prove it to you. In 1 Corinthians
chapter 15:51, the Bible says, "Behold,
I show you a mystery. We shall not all
sleep, but we shall all be changed in a
moment, in the twinkling of an eye, at
the last trump. For the trumpet shall
sound, for the trumpet shall sound, and
the dead shall be raised incorruptible,
and we shall be changed. For this
corruptible must put on incorruption,
and this mortal must put on immortality.
When do mortals put on immortality? When
they die. No.
The text clearly says at the last trump.
So if we are mortal before the last
trump, it means we're subject to death.
We all die and we remain dead until the
last trump. And when that trump sounds,
which is when Jesus comes again, then
and only then is immortality granted.
And it is not granted to the wicked,
y'all.
It is only granted to the righteous. The
reason why the righteous will be able to
enjoy the eternal Sabbath cycles of God
is because God grants them immortality
at the last trump. Which means that the
reason the wicked cannot burn in hell
forever is number one they are not
fireproof and number two they do not
have immortality.
They must become ashes.
And Malachi 4:3
demonstrates that you shall tread down
the wicked, for they shall be ashes
under the souls of your feet in the day
that I shall do this, sayaeth the Lord.
Here's what I need you to understand.
See? See the text? But the wicked shall
perish,
and the enemies of the Lord shall be as
the fat of the lambs. They shall consume
into smoke shall they consume away. The
smoke of their torment ascendeth up
forever. Why? Because the all that is
left of them is smoke. Smoke in the
atmosphere, ashes underneath their feet.
You know what's so powerful?
God promised Abraham that his seed would
be like the the dust of the ground would
be like the stars of the sky.
And what he was saying was, listen, I'm
going to resurrect
I'm going to resurrect your people out
of the tomb
and they're going to be as numerous as
the stars in the sky.
The end result of the wicked is they
become the dust.
They become the dust.
Those who reject the sanctifying power
and grace and memorial of of God
are rejecting.
They are placing themselves in a
position
in which rejecting the commandments of
God, the Bible clearly tells us, those
who do that do not enter the kingdom of
heaven. This is not a matter of choose
your day.
This is not a matter of well for me it's
good here, but for you if you choose to.
This is not a matter of of of choice
when it comes to the commandments of
God.
You see, beloved, the Bible tells us,
the Bible tells us, "Let us labor
therefore to enter into that rest, lest
any man fall after the same example of
unbelief." The rest that we are laboring
to enter is ultimately heaven itself.
But heaven itself is called God's
sabotismos. And what I need you to
understand is those who refuse to
sabotismos here on earth will not be
able to enter the sabatismos of heaven.
Why? Because in the sabatismos of heaven
in that heavenly place in that city
called New Jerusalem where remember the
gates of that city are going to honor
the Sabbath.
the gates of that city,
those within the gates of that city will
honor the Sabbath. We've read it. But
watch this. The Bible says in Revelation
15:2, "And I saw as it were a glass, a
sea of glass mingled with fire, and them
that had gotten the victory over the
beast and over his over his image and
over his mark and over the number of his
name stand on the sea of glass."
Beloved, if you are going to stand on a
sea of glass mingled with fire in
heaven, that means that you are
fireproof.
Only those
who are fireproof will be able to stand
in the presence of God and not be
consumed.
Daniel 7:9 tells us this. I beheld till
thrones were cast down and the ancient
of days did sit whose garment was white
as snow and the hair of his head like
the pure wool. His throne was like the
fiery flame and his wheels as burning
fire. A fiery stream issued and came
forth from before him. Thousand
thousands ministered unto him. 10,000
times 10,000 stood before him. The
judgment was set and the books were
open. And I need you to understand,
beloved, that if we're going to dwell in
the presence of this God, if we're going
to dwell in the presence of this fiery
throne, you better be fireproof.
And now, now
we're getting ready to close.
We're almost getting ready to close. I
got I got a few more things I need to
read you. I need you to follow along.
Isaiah 33. Please note with me Isaiah 33
beginning with verse 10.
The Bible says, "Now will I rise, sayeth
the Lord. Now will I be exalted. Now
will I lift up myself. You shall you
shall conceive chaff. Ye shall bring
forth stubble. Your breath as fire shall
devour you. And the people shall be as
the burnings of lime. As thorns cut up
shall they be burned in the fire."
Watch, watch, watch the next verse.
The sinners in Zion are afraid.
Fearfulness has surprised the
hypocrites. Who among us shall dwell
with a devouring fire? Who among us
shall dwell with everlasting burnings?
He that walketh righteously and speaketh
uprightly? He that despiseth the gain of
oppressions, that shaketh hands from
holding bribes, that stopth his ears
from hearing of blood, and shutth his
eyes from seeing evil, he shall dwell on
high. His place of defense shall be the
munitions of rocks. Bread shall be given
him. His water shall be sure. Thine eyes
shall see the king in his beauty. They
shall behold the land that is far off.
Watch this. Look on look upon Zion, the
city of our semimnities. Thine eye shall
see Jerusalem, a quiet habitation,
a tabernacle that shall not be taken
down. One of thy stakes of the of the
stakes therefore thereof shall never be
removed. Neither shall any of the cords
thereof be broken. But the g but there
the glorious Lord will be unto us a
place of broad rivers and streams
wherein shall go no gi with oes. Neither
shall gallon ships pass there pass
thereby. For the Lord is our judge. The
Lord is our lawgiver. The Lord is our
king. He will save us. Watch.
And the inhabitants shall not say, "I am
sick." The people that dwell therein
shall be forgiven their iniquity. Let me
pause for a second, y'all. Y'all need to
understand this. The devil is a liar.
The devil is a liar. The devil says it
is the wicked that will dwell with
everlasting burnings and has a whole
bunch of people terrified of this God
who is supposed to be love. Oh, the God
of love. If you don't obey him, he's
going to burn you forever and ever and
ever and ever. No. Isaiah says it is the
righteous that will burn forever, not
the wicked.
The righteous will dwell with
everlasting burnings, not the wicked.
The wicked are burnt up. Why? because
they refused to rest in the one that is
the sanctifier.
They refused
to walk
in the commandments of God. They refused
to live by the testimony of Jesus.
And as a result, they were not
fireproof.
They could not stand in the presence of
an eternally burning God and not be
consumed. It is no wonder then that
Revelation 22:14 and 15 tells us,
"Blessed are they that do his
commandments that they may have right to
the tree of life and may enter in
through the gates into the city. But
without are dogs and sorcerers and
whoreongers and murderers and idoltors
and whosoever loveth and maketh a lie.
You guys, I need you to understand this.
At the end of time, at the end of time,
when the wicked are destroyed,
they will see the righteous standing in
the presence of God. And like that
burning bush which was not consumed,
they will ask the question, how is it
that they're able to stand in the
presence of God and not be consumed?
And God is going to demonstrate to them
that the reason he cannot let them into
heaven is because it would be eternal
torment for them.
And eternally tormenting anyone is
outside of the character of God.
God is going to demonstrate what heaven
would be like if the wicked entered into
it.
And the way I like to put this, beloved,
is that God with his great big arms of
fire will embrace the wicked one last
time. And in that embrace
of the wicked, they will see
what it would be like to dwell in the
city of fire.
Because God is a fire. His throne is a
fire. There's a sea of glass mingle with
fire. His angels are ministering spirits
of fire. They would see what it would be
like
to dwell in the presence of holiness
while having sin upon them.
And watch this you all.
God in his mercy,
he will cause them to suffer
and then he will allow them
to rest
in death
forever
because that is the character of God.
The Sabbath you will keep is one you
will not come back from.
You will rest
in death forever.
The Bible says in Ecclesiastes 9 verse
10 verse uh Ecclesiastes 9 vers 5 and
six. The wicked know that they should
lie but the dead know not anything. The
fire will destroy the wicked and bring
them to a state of nonexistence
for ever.
And now I want to show you something. I
want to close with an appeal. And I need
you to see this. In the Old Testament,
God had given a commandment. Exodus 35:2
and 3. It says, "Six day shall work be
done, but on the seventh day there shall
be shall be to you a holy day, a Sabbath
of rest to the Lord. Whosoever doeth
work therein shall be put to death. You
shall kindle no fire throughout your
habitations upon the Sabbath day.
Now beloved, this is the Old Testament.
In the Old Testament, when you broke a
commandment, you were put to death in
the presence of God. That is not the
case in the New Testament. What is done
away in the New Testament is not the
commandment.
Honor your mother and father. You were
stoned for that in the Old Testament. In
the New Testament,
that commandment still stands. But the
stoning has been saved until the end of
time
when God will rain down hailstones on
the wicked. That's when the stoning
happens. The punishment is just delayed.
It's not done away with in the New
Testament. Punishment is delayed.
So, so but what I want you to see here
is that they were not supposed to gather
or they were not supposed to kindle fire
on the Sabbath while they were in the
wilderness. This is when the commandment
was given. They were not to kindle fire.
But the Bible says in Numbers 15:32 and
33, while the children of Israel were in
the wilderness, they found a man that
gathered sticks upon the Sabbath day.
And they that found him gathering sticks
brought him unto Moses and Aaron, and
unto all the congregation. And they put
him in a ward, because it was not
declared what should be done unto him.
And the Lord said unto Moses, "The man
shall be surely put to death, and all
the congregation shall stone him with
stones without the camp." Why was this
man
put to death? Let me tell you why. And
here's my appeal. Here's my appeal. But
I need to tell you why first.
Why would one gather sticks?
Why would he be out gathering sticks on
the day on on the Sabbath? We've got two
options. Two options. Not two options.
Two reasons.
Two reasons why someone would gather
sticks.
Number one.
Number one, you would gather sticks if
you if you were trying to set a fire
to keep yourself warm.
You would gather sticks if you were
trying to set a fire to keep yourself
warm.
Why would this be so offensive in the
sight of God?
I want you to notice with me Exodus 13
21 and 22.
And the Lord went before them by day in
a pillar of cloud to lead them the way
and by night in a pillar of fire to give
them light to go by day and night. He
took not away the pillar of the cloud by
day nor the pillar of fire by night from
before the people. God, listen to me
now. God in essence was saying, "Listen,
while we're here in the wilderness,
you will never need to light a fire
to keep yourself warm or for light
because I am your light. I am your
warmth."
So when this man went out and was and
was looking for stakes, if it was for
warmth or fire, he was saying, "I am not
satisfied with God's fire. I want to I
want to start my own fire.
There would be another reason. It would
be to cook. It would be to cook. And why
would that be an issue? Let's go to
Exodus 16:29.
See, for the Lord has given you this
Sabbath. Therefore, he has given you on
the sixth day the bread of two days.
Abide ye every man in his place. Let no
man go go out of his place on the
seventh day. God was saying, "Hey, I'm
going to provide for you. I'll be your
warmth. I'll be your food. I will be all
that you need. Therefore, while we're in
the wilderness, I'm taking care of you.
You don't need you don't need to kindle
a fire upon the Sabbath day because I
got you.
I am here for you. And so when the man
went out to grab sticks, what he was
saying was,
I can decide for myself.
I can determine for myself.
Yeah, God, I'm in the camp. I believe in
you. I see you. But you know what? I can
choose for myself what I think is right
and what is wrong.
And yet, even though you're saying
you're going to provide for me, I'm
still going to go ahead and work. I'm
gonna I'm still going to go ahead and do
my thing and provide for myself. Now, in
the New Testament, beloved, that
commandment doesn't stand kind of fire.
You can't kind of fire on the Sabbath.
That's not in the New Covenant. That's
not connected with the Sabbath. Now, but
I need you to understand something.
There are people who are still kindling
fire on the Sabbath day. Understand what
I mean, you guys? They are still
kindling fire, rejecting God's
providence, rejecting God saying, "Hey,
this day I want you to remember that I
am the one that sanctifies you. I want
you to remember that I got you. Don't
worry about your bills. Don't worry
about this. Don't worry about that. I
want you to know that I got you." And
people are saying, "Nah, I don't think
so. You know what this day means for me?
I have this to do and that to do and
that to do." And so, they are gathering
fire. They are kindling fire.
Please note, beloved, that this was the
thing God warned Jerusalem against in
Jeremiah 17:27. Then we have 1 verse 11.
We're going to close out. But if you
will not hearken unto me to how the
Sabbath day, and to not bear a burden,
even entering in at the gates of
Jerusalem on the Sabbath day, then will
I kindle a fire in the gates thereof,
and it shall devour the palaces of
Jerusalem. It shall not be quenched. You
break the Sabbath, you're going to deal
with fire that shall not be quenched.
The Sabbath is an outgrowth of the
character of God. Fire is an outgrowth
of the character of God. The reason both
of them stand together, the reason both
of them are eternal is because God
himself is eternal. And to reject one
means to be not prepared to stand in the
other. Lord, teach me to rest so that
when that fire comes upon this planet, I
will be like those who like in the days
of Noah when God rained water down on
the earth, the fish didn't die because
they were already fish creatures.
Everyone that was everything that was
not a sea creature died in the water. In
the same way, beloved, those who have
not been baptized by the spirit,
baptized with fire and obeying God's
word, obeying his commandments,
keeping his law, keeping the Sabbath,
resting as a reminder that he is the one
that sanctifies us. Those who continue
to light their own fires, or as Isaiah
50:1 says, "Behold all ye that kindle a
fire, that compass yourselves about with
sparks, walk in the light of your fire,
and in the sparks that you have kindled,
this shall you have of mine hand. You
shall lie down in sorrow." Beloved,
the devil has lied and said
it is the wicked that burn forever. And
if the wicked burns forever, that means
God is a vindictive
God. That means God is a God who has
millions of people scared. And the only
reason they are worshiping him is
because the idea of burning in hell
through all eternity terrifies them.
And there are people who literally
believe that using that that fear
tactic, you better be afraid,
will lead people to genuinely love God.
It is. It would be like someone holding
a gun to your head and saying, "Do you
love me?" What are you going to say?
Of course I love you. Will you marry me?
What are you going to say? Of course,
I'll marry you. Why? Because the gun is
to your head.
And this is what millions of Christians
believe evangelism is.
Show them what God will do to them if
they don't obey him.
And therefore, beloved, when you're
fearing God like that, you will do the
minimum amount it takes
to save you from that thing. So, if all
I have to do is confess Jesus with my
mouth, oh, that's it. That's all. All
right, I'll do that. And then you can
say to yourself, I believe that that
I've escaped that and now I can live how
I want to live. As long as I accepted
him with my mouth, I'm good to go. Why?
Because the love is not generated. The
love is not generated from love. It was
generated from fear. It was generated
from the spirit of fear. And when you're
doing something out of fear, you will
always do the minimal thing that you
think it takes to get you out of that
scary thing. Yes, somebody needs to get
this sermon
to Cameron Kirk. Someone needs to get
this message to all those people who
believe that the Sabbath is a day that
you can choose. You can choose your own
day, you know, it doesn't matter.
Someone needs to to to get this kind of
message to the world to help them to
understand
that God is trying to set them on fire.
Now
he's trying to set your heart on fire
now so that when he comes back again you
will not be afraid of him. Why? Because
as he is fire you are fire. And fire is
not afraid of fire.
For those of you who who are watching
and you may be hearing this for the
first time
and in your mind you're like this is
liberating.
I have been living in fear of God
thinking that it was his desire to burn
the wicked in hell forever. Now I see it
is a lie. Lord, I thank you for opening
my eyes. Thank you for helping me to to
just stumble upon this sermon,
Lord. Help me to study deeper. What else
have I been lied to about?
What else have I taken for granted that
was truth? I heard that the Sabbath was
done away with, but now I'm saying,
"Wait a minute.
If the fire of God is is eternal, which
it is, then the Sabbath of God must be
eternal, too. And if I want to be able
to stand in that fire and not be
consumed,
I've got to be sanctified by this one
who sanctified the Sabbath back there at
creation. So I can live forever and not
be consumed.
So I can live forever and and and and
honor that weekly Sabbath eternal cycle.
So come on, put put that one in the
chat.
Lord,
sanctify me.
May I never forget your your your symbol
of sanctification.
Remind me that I'm sanctified in Christ.
And may I never forget to remember what
you said to remember.
I want to enter into that eternal rest
and I want to be able to stand in the
fiery presence of God and not be
consumed. Let me say it this way. I want
to burn.
I want to burn
for I want to burn like that burning
bush burned in the presence of God but
was not consumed. Lord, help me to be
like Shadrach, Meshach, and Abednego.
Help me to stand in your fiery furnace.
Help me to stand in your fiery presence
and not be like the wicked who will be
destroyed by the fire, but be like the
righteous who will be able to stand on
that sea of glass mingle with fire and
not be consumed. I see all the ones in
the chat. May God equip you. May God set
you on fire. May God make you fireproof
is my prayer
in Jesus name.
Amen. Heavenly Father,
we thank you for speaking to us today.
We thank you, Lord, for showing us this
connection between fire and rest.
Lord, they are both a reflection of your
character. And because you are eternal,
they are eternal.
Help us not to believe the devil's lie
that the Sabbath is not eternal and that
the fire and the that the wicked
are eternal and will suffer eternally.
The devil has flipped this
and is confusing millions of Christians.
Please, Lord.
Not only is he confusing Christians,
he's confusing the world as they hear
Christians saying, "The wicked will be
burned forever." And they're saying,
"What kind of a God is that? What kind
of a God of love is that?" Lord, please
vindicate your character
and reveal the lie of the enemy to as
many souls as will listen. This we pray
in Jesus name. Amen. And amen. We're
going to go ahead and put that link for
our afterglow discussion in the chat.
Our afterglow discussion, everyone is
invited to come and at the afterlow
discussion, we're going to simply talk
about our Sabbath school. We're going to
talk about this message today and uh and
share how the Lord has spoken to you
through this message. So, it is a place
where we kind of get to fellowship
together. So, again, everyone is
invited. Um, for those of you who are
interested in learning more and maybe
even getting into Bible studies to learn
more, I'm going to put this last slide
up on the screen. You can see you can
contact Bible worker at living.urch.
You can also follow us on social media
um um by scanning those QR codes and
connect with Living Mana online. And
again, may God bless you, may God keep
you, may God empower you, may God set
your heart on fire, and may God make you
fireproof, and may God grant you rest.
Amen and amen.
Thank you for joining us today. If this
is your first time worshiping with us,
please check out our website at
livingmana.urch.
We are not just here for Sabbath
service. We have weekly programming too
that covers mental health, physical
health, weekly prayer service, financial
health, and proving the existence of
God. It is our desire that our
programming will continue to bless you.
Please continue to pray for us as we
fulfill God's mission to go into all the
world with the gospel of Jesus Christ.